-=THE LAST FANTASY=- Proudly Presents
-=THE LAST FANTASY=- 榮譽出品 本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用于商業途徑
- You bringing Micky in? - Yeah, he's gonna come.
- 你要把米奇也拍進來嗎？ - 是，他就要來了
He should be here as well.
1993年馬薩諸塞州洛厄爾市
You think he'll answer questions?
你認為他會回答問題嗎？
They said it was gonna be both of us here.
他們說會是我們倆一起回答
- Am I looking right in the camera here? - Just look at me, right here.
- 鏡頭正好對准我了嗎？ - 現在只要看我這里
All right. You don't want me to look in the camera with the...
- 好吧，你不想我在采訪中看鏡頭嗎？ - 看這里
I started boxing when I was 12 years old,
我12歲起開始練拳擊
and I'd lie and say I was 18, or whatever it was.
當時我騙他們滿18歲還是別的什么
You know, I had a different name and everything.
我換了全新的名字和其他一些東西
I mean, I don't know how many fights...
我是說，我不知道打了多少場
I'd done a hundred, more than that, before I turned professional.
在我成為專業拳擊手之前 打了大概一百多場的樣子
- Go ahead and sit right there. - Why we doing this?
- 到鏡頭前面去坐在那里 - 為什么我們要接受采訪？
- I don't wanna do this. - You want to start again?
- 我不想接受采訪 - 你想重來一遍？
This is my younger brother. I taught him everything he knows.
他是我弟弟，他知道的都是我教的
I'm still his trainer. You know, we got different styles.
我還是他的教練，盡管我倆拳擊技法不一樣
I'm fuckin' squirrelly as fuck. I'm like... I'm not even there.
我他媽的身法敏捷，動如脫兔
You know, that's what Sugar Ray said.
這話是舒格﹒雷說的
I was the most tricky fighter he'd ever come across.
他說我是他見過的最難纏的拳擊手
In '78, I fought Sugar Ray Leonard.
迪奇﹒埃克隆對舒格﹒雷﹒倫納德 馬薩諸塞州波士頓，1978年7月18日
I went toe-to-toe with him. He couldn't get to me.
我跟他近戰，他都不能近我身
They called me the pride... the pride of Lowell.
他們稱我為：驕傲，“洛厄爾之驕傲”
Everybody still talks about it, especially my brother.
現在大家還常說起此事，尤其是我弟弟
His whole life he wanted to do what I did, you know?
他每時每刻都夢想到達我的高度
But we're very different fighters.
不過我倆是不同的拳擊手
Micky's, you know, he's a heavy hitter.
米奇出拳很重
He's got... a thunderous,
強勁的擊打
I'm telling you, thunderous left punch.
雷擊般強力的左勾拳
Micky, he gets you and he takes a punishment,
米奇會靠近你，他抗擊打能力很強
I don't know why he does it, till you're right fuckin' in there.
我不知道為什么他那么做 你只有身臨其境才知道
He likes getting on the inside, I stay on the outside.
他喜歡近身肉搏，我喜歡游擊移動
Come on.
別鬧了
Dicky.
迪奇
Would you come on?
你能過來下么？
Will you stop? You gotta help me finish this.
你能停會么？幫我干完這活
Come on!
還鬧！
- And predictable as ever. - All right.
- 結果會和往常一樣 - 好吧
- You don't need to be Columbo - Here you go.
- 不用神探科倫坡也知道誰會贏 - 來
To see where this fight is headed.
看看這局誰會贏
Bam! Over right hand puts Micky Ward down!
砰！一記右拳就把米奇﹒沃德打倒了！
HBO's making a movie on me and my comeback!
HBO在拍一部我復出的電影！
And my brother is gonna beat Saoul Mamby in Atlantic City next week!
還有我弟弟下周要在亞特蘭大 痛扁賽奧爾﹒曼比！
The pride of Lowell is back!
“洛厄爾之驕傲”回來了！
Quacka! Who wants some?!
哈哈！誰還想試試？！
Hey! I want a cut.
* 現在我已經是個很壞很壞的人了 *
Are you good? You guys having a good day?
你還好嗎？大伙今天過得都不錯？
How are ya?
你呢？
Come on! What you got? What you got going on?
來！看你有几下子？下面想干嘛？
Lou! Hey, Lou!
盧！嘿！
- How are you guys? - Dicky.
- 你們怎么樣？ - 迪奇
Making my comeback.
我要復出了
Hey, naughty, naughty. What's going on here?
嘿，淘氣鬼們，在這干嘛？
Hey, Dicky, Micky! Take my picture.
* 記得當時 *
- Take a picture? - Yeah.
- 拍照？ - 嗯
- Hey! - Hey, Louie!
- 嘿！ - 嘿，路易！
HBO's making a movie on me!
HBO在給我拍電影！
What's going on? Hey, beautiful.
怎么了？嘿，美女
Did you tap that?
你還和她搞過？
I can't remember. I got CRS: I Can't Remember Shit!
我不記得了，我有我擦淚記不住綜合症 我勒個去記不住啊
Hey, Jerry Garcia!
* 你是否還會給我…？ *
Are you nuts?
你這個蠢蛋
How'd you get here? You drive around?
怎么到這了？隨便轉轉？
Hey, Ray. Ray. I love you, Ray.
嘿，雷，嘿，我愛你
You're doing well.
你做的很好
You're walking. Get on it.
你還沒趴下，繼續吧
- We make a mistake? - Nah, I mean, he'll be here.
- 我們弄錯了？ - 不，他會來的
You know, like I said, sometimes he goes on his own schedule
像我說的，有時候他有他自己的打算
but when he gets here, we work hard. You know, nobody pushes me harder.
但他一來我們就會刻苦訓練的 他逼我逼得最緊了
He's supposed to be training you right now, right?
他本該現在訓練你的，對吧？
Why don't you just go talk to them, my sisters? They'll talk your ear off.
你干脆跟我姐姐們說會話 她們能說得你耳朵生繭
You gotta pay them to shut up.
你得花錢才能讓她們閉嘴
He can tell you how Dicky was helping him.
他可以講講迪奇怎么幫他的
Yeah, come on, Micky.
說說，米奇
- O'Keefe! - Hey, we don't know where Dicky is.
- 奧基夫！ - 嘿，我們不知道迪奇去哪了！
You know where he is.
你知道他在哪
What's that Keystone Kop doing in there? Where's Dicky? Girls?
那個蠢警察在那干嘛？ 姑娘們，迪奇呢？
- I don't know. - Did you see him, your brother?
- 我不知道 - 你沒有看見你兄弟？
- Not this morning? - Look at Ma!
- 今早沒有 - 看看媽媽！
All dressed up for the movie, huh?
為電影盛裝而來？
- Wow! - Get outta the ring, O'Keefe.
- 哇！ - 奧基夫，從拳擊台上下來
My Dicky should be doing that, huh?
我的迪奇才該在上面
Your Dicky ain't here, Alice.
你家迪奇不在這，愛麗絲
Micky's got an important fight coming up and he's not training.
米奇有場很重要的比賽 而他卻不訓練自己的弟弟
Don't. Just forget about him.
不管了，別理他了
He's number two man. He's not part of this, all right?
他是非重要人物 他不參加電影的拍攝，是吧？
- He's not being handled right. - You get me coming in all right?
- 米奇沒接受正確的訓練 - 你拍到我走來的鏡頭嗎？
You want me to do that again?
你想我重走一次嗎？
Get out of the ring, O'Keefe. Dicky's the trainer.
奧基夫，從拳擊台上下來，迪奇才是教練
- I'm doing a favor, Alice. - I will show you over here
- 我是在幫忙，愛麗絲 - 我在這里給你們看
these scrapbooks I've been collecting for years.
這是我收集了好多年的剪貼簿
Micky used to follow his big brother everywhere.
米奇以前常常跟著他哥哥到處跑
Taught ya everything, didn't he, honey?
是他教會你一切，是吧，親愛的？
In '78, we got the offer to fight Sugar Ray Leonard.
在1978年，我們受邀 跟舒格﹒雷﹒倫納德比賽
Oh, my God, it was... Have you seen that video?
哦，天吶，你看過錄像沒？
Oh, you're from HBO. You gotta see it again. Come on.
哦，你是HBO的記者，你得再看一次，來嘛
Art, Art, where's the video at?
阿特，錄像放哪了？
Tonight, my son is gonna surprise everybody and beat Sugar Ray Leonard.
今晚我兒子會令所有人驚訝 并打敗舒格﹒雷﹒倫納德
Believe me, I know it.
相信我，我很清楚
Sugar Ray might have some trouble tonight.
舒格﹒雷今晚可能會有麻煩了
That's a good possibility. He comes in here against a good boxer,
這是件好事，他到此與一位優秀拳手較量
a young man who can punch, and I would like to say at this time
一個很能打的年輕人
Leonard is down. Let's see if that's a knockdown.
倫納德倒下了 我們看看這是不是有效擊倒
This is unbelievable.
不可思議
Eklund just walked over him!
埃克隆從他身上跨了過去
Nobody seems to know what's happening!
沒人意識到剛剛發生了什么！
Dicky did it. Yeah. Tricky Dicky did it.
迪奇做到了，是的，狡猾的迪奇成功了
- Dicky did it. - Weren't you supposed to be
- 迪奇成功了 - 你現在不是應該在訓練米奇嗎？
- No, it ain't till 9:00. - Dicky, it's fucking 11:45!
- 不，到9點才開始 - 現在已經他媽的11:45了！
- It's 11:45, Dick. - What?!
- 是真的，迪克 - 什么？！
Where'd you fuckin' park the car, Boo Boo?!
你他媽的把車停哪了，布布？
I didn't park it. You did. I didn't park it.
不是我停的，是你停的，我沒有停
Check your fuckin' pockets for the keys.
看看你口袋里有鑰匙沒
- You got the keys, yeah? - I didn't park it, man.
- 鑰匙在你那吧？ - 不是我停的車，兄弟
- Down there? I don't know. - Check your pockets, all right?
- 停在那邊？我不知道 - 看看你口袋，好吧？
- You're fuckin' mental. - Fuck it!
- 你真他媽瘋了！ - 靠
I'll run. I need the fuckin' roadwork.
我得跑著去了，我他媽很久沒長跑了
- Roadwork? Are you crazy? - He's a great runner.
- 長跑？你瘋了？ - 他是跑步健將
Hey.
嘿
Hey!
嘿！
Quacka!
喂喂！
- Hey, Dicky. - Better late than never.
- 嘿，迪奇 - 晚來總比不來好
Oh, look! Detective's on the scene.
看！神探到了
Gonna get to the bottom of this.
要來查清這件事的真相
- Figure this one out, huh? - Dick, you're an asshole.
- 理清頭緒了？ - 迪克，你是個混蛋
Hold it, hold it. Let me get this straight.
等等，等等，我先弄清楚
You guys are working in the same corner as Micky, together, right?
你們倆和米奇在一個拳擊館工作，是吧？
Yeah. Yeah, they're both in my corner, and this is what goes on.
對，對，他們倆都和我一起干，就是這樣
OK.
好
Don't you have a job to go to or something?
你沒別的工作要做嗎？
Really, O'Keefe has a job that he should be at.
真的，奧基夫應該去上班了
Yeah, Sergeant O'Keefe's working overtime here.
嗯，奧基夫警官在這加班呢
So we got Saoul Mamby, Jewish, black, former world champ.
我們要對付的是賽奧爾﹒曼比 猶太人，黑人，前世界冠軍
I think we got all the bases covered.
我們對對手了解夠詳細了
And my kid brother, he's lost three fights in a row.
而我的弟弟，已經連輸3場了
You know, he can't get used to losing. It's a mental thing.
他不能習慣于輸，這會造成心理陰影
But we're gonna break that with Mamby, right?
不過我們不會再輸給曼比了，對吧？
Yeah, I hope, if we can train...
嗯，希望如此，如果我們訓練的話
We can train, right. Enough of you wasting time, Mick. You know?
我們當然會訓練，別浪費時間了，麥克
- Wasting time? - Half the fuckin' day's gone!
- 浪費時間？ - 已經過去一上午了！
- We got work to do. - Yeah, half the day's gone,
- 我們還得訓練 - 是，上午已經過了
- and I been waiting here for you. - You wanna win?
- 那是因為我在等你 - 你想贏？
Jab, two, three, four. Left, right, punch right. Jab...
刺拳，二三四，左右 從右邊進攻，再次刺拳
And again! One, two, three, four...
再來一次！一二三四
One, two, three, four, five... Jab, jab...
一二三四五，刺拳，刺拳
There you go! There you go!
就是這樣！就是這樣！
Come on, move! Might as well drop the weight,
來，動起來！可能只要他放下失敗的包袱
we're gonna out-box Mamby.
我們會擊敗曼比
- Take it out on the mitts. - Head, body, head.
* 扭曲不潔的空氣 *
That's your fuckin' combo. Head, body, head.
這才是連擊，頭，身體，頭
Head, body, head, body. My Dicky taught him that.
頭，身體，頭，身體，我家迪奇這么教他的
You know, Sugar Ray's gonna be there,
舒格﹒雷會到場
calling the fight for ESPN.
為ESPN解說比賽（美國娛樂體育節目電視網）
I ain't seen him since I knocked him down.
我自從打敗他之后就沒再見過他了
Like 14 years ago or somethin'. Right?
貌似是14年前吧？
Hook!
勾拳！
Let's get a real sparring going on here.
讓我們打場真正的拳擊
Don't wanna embarrass yourself.
別讓自己丟臉
Don't wanna embarrass yourself in front of Sugar Ray, do you, Mick?
別在舒格﹒雷面前給自己丟臉，知道嗎？
- You got him... - Come on. Head, body, head!
- 他肯定不會的 - 來，頭，身體，頭
Fuck.
靠
- Fuckin' yeah. That's your punch, Mick. - Oh, my God.
- 真他媽精彩，這才是你的重拳，麥克 - 天吶
That's your punch.
這才是你的重拳
That's your liver punch. It shuts the whole fuckin' body down.
拳就該打在肝臟那兒 那是整個身體的脆弱點
George's fingers are so fuckin' fat, he can't even dial the phone!
喬治的手指頭太胖了，連電話都撥不了
Hey, right there, Tar!
嘿，看這個，塔爾
That's not helping, George!
豎中指可沒用，喬治！
- Hold on. Wait a minute. I'm confused. - What?
- 等等，我搞不清楚了 - 什么？
- Yeah, I'm confused, too. - We're confused.
- 我也搞不清楚了 - 我們都搞不清了
- George is whose father? - You're confused?
- 喬治是誰的老爸？ - 你搞不清楚？
- Dick Eklund Sr. Is Dicky's... - Donna's, Gail's and Phyllis's father.
- 老迪克﹒埃克隆是迪奇的… - 唐娜的，蓋爾的和菲莉斯的父親
- Is Dick Eklund. - Yeah.
- 是迪克﹒埃克隆 - 是
And even though Alice is an Eklund, so is Cindy and Cathy,
盡管愛麗絲也姓埃克隆，辛迪和凱西也是
- George is really their... - And Micky...
- 喬治真是他們的… - 還有米奇
- No. Micky and I are... - Sherri Ward.
- 不，米奇和我的父親是… - 謝里﹒沃德
- We're Wards. - The Wards.
- 我們是沃德家的 - 沃德家
It's not the way it sounds. Dick Eklund and I were separated, right?
其實并不是聽起來這樣 迪克﹒埃克隆和我早分居了
And then there was George, just George. George is my man.
然后就是喬治，只有喬治，他才是我的男人
- Georgie's our poppa. - After Dick, it was just George.
- 喬治是我們的爸爸 - 在迪克之后，我就只有喬治一個男人
Charlene! Charlene!
沙琳！沙琳！
Hey, Charlene!
嘿，沙琳！
- We're doing shots with Charlene! - Yeah, you get over here.
- 沙琳，來一口干 - 嗯，你來這邊
- Come on! Come over here. - Come on, drink yours.
- 來，到這來 - 來，干了你的
On the count of three... Three!
數到三…，三
Good job, fellas. Oh, hey, one more time.
不錯，伙計們，嘿，再來一次
Why don't you just go talk to her? She's a nice girl.
你干嘛不找她說話？她人挺好的
I told her all about you.
我跟她說過你
I don't wanna ask her if she's gonna say no.
我不想約她，她會拒絕的
Can't beat that ass, can ya?
抗拒不了那翹臀吧？
Get out of the booth. Come on. Come on.
站起來，快去
Are you just gonna stand there and stare at my ass?
你就打算一直站在那盯著我屁股看么？
Your father stares at my ass, but he talks to me.
你爸也盯著我屁股看，不過他跟我說話了
Thinks you're the greatest.
他覺得你是最棒的
- He didn't tell me you were mute. - Keep the change, doll.
- 不過他沒告訴我你是啞巴 - 不用找了，小妞
He told me you're Kenny Fleming's sister.
他告訴我你是肯尼﹒弗萊明的妹妹
- This is a tip? - Yeah, that's my tip.
- 這是小費？ - 嗯，我給的小費
You know what the bell says about this tip?
你知道這個鈴會說什么嗎？
Cheap bastard. Cheap fucker.
吝嗇雜種，小氣混蛋
Comes in here every day, gives me shitty tips.
每天都來，給我這么少小費
- Fuck that. - Yeah, fuck you, too.
- 操 - 操你
- Forget it, boys... - You pave streets, right?
- 別管她，伙計們 - 你是鋪路工，是嗎？
- Yeah, I do. And I'm a fighter. - Oh, yeah,
- 是，我還是拳擊手 - 是
I heard you were a stepping-stone.
我聽說你是個墊腳石
- No, I'm no stepping-stone. - You're the guy they use,
- 我不是墊腳石 - 他們利用你
against the other fighters to move the other fighters up.
和其他拳手比賽來抬高他們
I've had a few tough fights, but that's not who I am.
我有几場打得比較艱難，不過我可不弱
The next fight's gonna show who I am.
下一場會展示出我的實力
Yeah, and he's gonna lose that one, too.
嗯，下一場他也會輸掉
Scotch and soda, Charlene. And one for yourself.
蘇打威士忌，沙琳，給你也來一杯
So move that sugar ass and get my...
扭扭你的小屁股，給我…
You be nice. OK?
你得禮貌點
Be respectful. Don't disrespect her.
放尊重點，不許對她無禮
Hey, don't hurt your hands. We got a fight next week.
嘿，別傷了你的手，下周還有比賽呢
Besides, you wipe your ass with that one.
你還得用那只手擦屁股呢
Don't lean up, or I'm gonna hit you in the cocksucker.
別待在這，否則我揍扁你這混蛋
- He's gonna beat Saoul Mamby, say it! - Yeah, he's gonna beat him!
- 他會打敗賽奧爾﹒曼比，說！ - 是，他會打敗曼比！
Right? Right? Hey!
聽懂了嗎？聽懂了嗎？
- Right. - That's right!
- 嗯 - 這就對了
I'm gonna take your drink, as well. I'm taking his drink.
我會把你的酒也喝了，給我他的酒
Hey, this guy's gonna be champion. He's a great guy.
這個家伙會當冠軍的，他人很不錯
He's a great fighter. You can't go wrong. Thanks for the drink.
也是個很棒的拳手，你不會選錯的 謝謝這杯酒
Those cameras are makin' a movie about him.
那些攝像機在拍一部關于他的電影呢
He knocked down Sugar Ray Leonard on HBO,
在HBO電視節目上 他打倒了舒格﹒雷﹒倫納德
that's why they're following him around with the camera.
所以他們一直扛著攝像機拍攝他
And now they're making a movie about his comeback.
他們在拍攝有關他復出的電影
Yeah, everybody's talking about it. But who are you fightin'?
是啊，大家都在談論這事 不過你下面要和誰比賽？
- Saoul Mamby. - Saoul Mamby?
- 賽奧爾﹒曼比 - 賽奧爾﹒曼比？
- What kind of name is that? - Black and Jewish.
- 什么人會起這種名字？ - 猶太黑人
Where did they find a guy like that?
他們哪兒找來的這人的？
He's no joke. Former world champ.
他可不是小人物，前世界冠軍
- Former champ? - Yeah.
- 前任冠軍？ - 是
- I match up good with him though. - Yeah?
- 不過我和他實力相當 - 是嗎？
- Yeah. - What does that mean?
- 是 - 這話什么意思？
Well, I got lighter, you know? I have a reputation for brawlin',
我步法更輕盈了，我徒手搏擊很厲害
but I'm not gonna brawl with him. I'm gonna try and out-box him.
不過我不跟他比徒手搏擊，我跟他比拳擊
- And there's a difference? - Yeah, you know.
- 有什么不同嗎？ - 是
Brawlin', you slug it out. I hit you, you hit me.
徒手搏擊一定要一較高下，我打你，你打我
Boxing's a chess game, you know? I pick my punches to take him down.
拳擊則是一場博弈，我得重拳擊倒他
And go head, body, head, body.
不斷進攻頭，身體，頭，身體
- What is "head, body, head, body"? - Well, I hit him in the head,
- 什么是“頭，身體，頭，身體”？ - 我打他的頭
and then his hand's gonna go up to protect himself,
他的手就必須抬起來護住頭部
so it opens up his body, and then when I hit him in the body,
就暴露了他的身體，然后我就打他的身體
the hand goes back down, I go back up to the head,
他的手又得下來，我再回去打頭
hand goes back up, hit him in the body.
他手又回到頭部，我再來打他的身體
People who don't know fighting think you can do a lot of damage
不懂拳擊的人會覺得打中頭部
hitting somebody in the head, but you do more hitting 'em in the body.
傷害比較大，但擊中對手身體傷害更大
So what do you think? Can I take you out?
你覺得我怎樣？可以和你約會嗎？
Are you married?
你結婚了？
No. Would I ask you out if I was married?
沒，結婚了怎么會約你出去？
- What kind of guy do you think I am? - Happens all the time. Trust me.
- 你把我想成什么人了？ - 這種事時有發生，相信我
I'm not like that.
我不是那種人
I'm not married. I got a daughter. I see her every other weekend.
我沒有結婚，我有個女兒 我每兩周去看她一次
Her name's Kasie. But that's it.
她叫凱西，就這樣而已
Come on. Let me take you out.
來，跟我約會吧
When?
什么時候？
Saturday night. I get back from Atlantic City.
周六晚，我從大西洋城回來
- Is this the real number? - You have to call it and see.
- 這是真的號碼嗎？ - 你可以撥撥看
I will. Saturday. Dinner and a movie.
我會的，周六，晚餐加電影
- Hey. Jimmy. - Micky, hey. How's it going?
- 嘿，吉米 - 米奇，最近怎么樣
I don't think Laurie's expecting you right now.
勞里肯定沒想到你現在會過來
What's he doin' here? This isn't your visitation day, Micky.
他在這兒干嘛？ 米奇，今天不是你探視的日子
Look, I just want to say hi to Kasie.
我就想跟凱西問聲好
It's not your day. Good-bye.
今天不該你探視，再見
Yeah, but I'm not around next weekend.
是，但我下周末不在這兒
- You ditchin' the days you do have? - No, I have a fight. I told you that.
- 你放棄那些天的探視了？ - 不，我有比賽，我告訴過你的
- Jimmy... - I can't get in the middle.
- 吉米… - 我不能插手
I can't talk to her, OK? So I'm asking you, Jimmy.
我無法和她說話了，好嗎？拜托了，吉米
I want to talk to my daughter. Now.
我現在想和我女兒說說話
- Talk to your father. - Goddamn it, Jimmy.
- 和你爸說話吧 - 該死，吉米
Daddy's gonna fight Saoul Mamby.
爸爸要和賽奧爾﹒曼比打
That's right. I want to tell you that after I win,
對，爸爸想贏了再告訴你的
I'm gonna start making good money, and I'll move into a bigger apartment
爸爸贏了就有丰厚的獎金 會搬進大點的公寓
like we talked about so you can live with me more days, OK?
我們以前說過的 那樣你就能跟我多住几天了，好嗎？
- Yeah, bigger apartment! - Wish me luck, all right?
- 好哦，更大的房子！ - 祝我好運，好不好？
Don't hold your breath, Kasie. It's cruel to mislead your child, Micky.
別抱太大希望，凱西 你這么騙自己孩子很殘忍，米奇
Good luck, Daddy.
祝你好運，爸爸
Thanks, Kasie. I love you, honey. Bye, baby.
謝謝，凱西，我愛你，甜心，再見，寶貝
Where is he?
他去哪了？
Jesus Christ. Un-fucking-believable.
神吶，真他媽不可思議
- Quit worrying, for crying out loud. - Blow that shit in my face.
- 別擔心了，搞什么名堂 - 別把煙噴我臉上
You know, it's none of my business. I go to a lot of meetings,
我知道不關我的事，我見了很多人
and they have a saying, "Let Go and Let God."
他們都說：“放手由他去吧”
- You gotta let him go, Mick. - He's taught me everything I know.
- 你得放手由他去，米奇 - 是他教會了我一切
He's been in my corner. I can't do it without him.
是他幫了我，沒有他就沒有我的今天
You're already doing it without him.
你已經沒他了，不也好好的
- No, I'm not. - Yes, you are.
- 不，我沒有 - 你有
Look, you know where he is. Why don't you just go get him?
你知道他在哪兒，干嘛不把他直接帶來？
- Can you get him? - I'm not fuckin' going to get him.
- 你能把他帶來嗎？ - 鬼才會去找他呢
Are we all gonna go over there in the limo with Alice? We can't do that.
那我們一批人和愛麗絲一起坐轎車去那兒？ 我們不能那么做
Dicky.
迪奇
- Your mother's outside. - What?
- 你媽在外面呢 - 什么？
Dicky, your mother's outside! She's down there!
迪奇， 你媽在外面！在下面！
I'm not here.
說我不在
- Oh, no. - What?
- 不要這樣 - 什么？
- I gotta go check... - Dicky, no!
- 我要去檢查… - 迪奇，不要！
Don't, Dicky! Dicky!
別這樣，迪奇！迪奇！
- He's goin'... - Dicky...
- 他要… - 迪奇
...better get out of here. - Dicky, no!
- 最好離開這里 - 迪奇，不要！
Quacka, what the fuck are you doing?
喂，你該死的在這干嘛？
You know we gotta go to the airport now. We got a flight to catch.
你知道我們現在得去機場的 我們還得趕飛機呢
You know how important this fight is to me.
你知道這場比賽對我有多重要嗎
Hey, don't tell Ma I'm here, all right?
別跟媽媽說我在這兒，可以嗎？
- She knows! - No, no, no.
- 她知道！ - 別，別
- Pick me up back at the house. - Are you fucking...
- 去屋后接我 - 你他媽
- I'll go through the yards. - She's in the driveway right now.
- 我從后院走 - 她現在就在車道呢
All right, but hurry up. She's in the fuckin' driveway.
好吧，不過快點，她就站在車道上呢
- We got a flight to catch. - You son of a bitch.
- 我們還得去趕飛機 - 你這個婊子養的
You do this on the day your brother's traveling?!
你弟弟走這天你就做這種事？！
What are you doing?
你這是干嘛？
- Why'd you make me do that? - What the fuck you hit him for?
- 為什么你逼我打你？ - 你打他干什么？
Why'd you make me do that to you?
為什么你逼我打你？
- Jesus! - Oh, my God, Dicky.
- 神吶！ - 天，迪奇！
I was on my way! Ma...
我正在趕去呢，媽媽
- What are you doing in this place? - There you go. There you go.
- 你們在這里做什么？ - 你看來了吧
Why can't we just go to the fuckin' airport for once, please?
為什么我們就不能有一次正常趕去機場呢？
- We got a plane to catch. - Hey, Alice, what about your husband?
- 我們還有飛機要趕 - 愛麗絲， 你丈夫怎么辦呢？
He's laying on the fuckin' ground. You wanna help your husband?
他躺在地上了，你都不幫他一下？
What are you doing running in here like a silverback fuckin' gorilla?
你像個銀背大猩猩一樣跑來這兒干嘛？
- We had to get him, for Chrissakes. - Yeah, you got him all right.
- 看在上帝份上，我們得找到他 - 是，你倒是找到他了
You got him, pal.
你惹毛他了，兄弟
You see Mamby? You see how Mamby's arm comes up?
你看到曼比了？看到他怎么抬手防御了？
Leaves his side open, you just light him up like a pinball machine.
這樣就暴露了他的側面 你就可以像玩彈球機一樣玩死他
He's gonna be pissin' blood. No way you lose, Mick. No way.
他會大出血，你絕不可能輸的，米奇，不會
- Hey, Lou. - Dicky boy.
- 嘿，盧 - 迪奇小子
Hey, listen, what? ESPN can't get us better rooms than this?
嘿，聽著，ESPN就不能 給我們弄個比這好點的房間嗎？
I wouldn't worry about the rooms right now, Dicky.
迪奇，現在別管什么房間了
- We got bigger headaches. - Like what?
- 還有更大的事要頭疼 - 比如？
- Doctor won't let Mamby fight. - Why not?
- 醫生不讓曼比比賽 - 為什么？
- He's got the flu. - Mamby got the flu?
- 他得了流感 - 曼比得了流感？
Yeah.
嗯
Micky, we can still have a fight.
米奇，我們還是能比賽的
- With who? - Mike Mungin.
- 和誰打？ - 邁克﹒曼津
Mike who, Mungin? Who's that?
邁克﹒誰？曼津？誰？
Guy from Philly? Isn't he in prison?
費城來的，他不是在監獄嗎？
He's been out a few months. I've called everybody, checked everywhere.
剛放出來几個月 我已經給所有人打過電話，查過所有地方
He's the only guy I could find.
我只能找到他了
My last few fights were rough, Lou. This one's supposed to be easier.
我前几場比賽已經打得很累了，盧 本想著這場輕松點的
I mean, we've been fuckin' preparing for Mamby.
我們一直都在准備和曼比打
Yeah, but this guy just came off the couch.
是的，不過這家伙疏于訓練
He's been sittin' on his ass. Could be an easy win for Mick.
整天無所事事，對米奇來說贏應該很輕松
Joey Ferrell, remember him? He knocked his ass out.
喬伊﹒費雷爾，記得他嗎？ 這人痛扁了他一頓
Micky knocked out Joey Ferrell.
而米奇又打敗了喬伊﹒費雷爾
Exactly. And Mungin just got off the couch.
沒錯，而且曼津疏于訓練
Can't make weight. Might be a bit over, though.
不能測精確的體重，不過他可能比你重些
- How over? - Maybe 162, 165.
- 重多少？ - 大概162還是165磅
One-sixty-five? Micky dropped weight. He's 146.
165磅？米奇減重了，他才146磅
Lou, we prepared for Mamby. All right? We prepared for Mamby.
盧，我們准備和曼比打的，對吧？ 我們准備的是和他打
This guy just got off the couch. Micky's in shape.
那家伙游手好閑，而米奇正狀態良好
Roadwork, everything else. This other guy, he hasn't done dick.
進行過長跑等訓練，而那家伙啥也沒練
Don't forget, you don't fight, nobody gets paid.
別忘了，你不比賽，大家都賺不到
OK.
好
So, Lou... Come on, please.
盧，拜托
Mick... Joey Ferrell knocked him out.
米奇…喬伊﹒費雷爾打敗過他
Gonna be a hell of a fight, huh?
會是場殘酷對決，對吧？
- I'm not doing this. 165 is big. - You knocked out Joey Ferrell.
- 我不同意，165磅太重了 - 你擊敗過喬伊﹒費雷爾
- So what? He's a middleweight. - He just got off the couch.
- 那又怎樣？他是中量級的 - 他疏于訓練
He's got 20 pounds on me, Dicky.
迪奇，他比我重20磅
Joey Ferrell knocked him out, you knocked out Joey Ferrell.
喬伊﹒費雷爾擊敗過他 你擊敗過喬伊﹒費雷爾
- You just said that. - Yeah, right. You can't be scared.
- 你已經說過了 - 對，你要無所畏懼
- Scared? - Yeah.
- 害怕？ - 對
- Why don't you go fuckin' fight him? - I'll go fuckin' fight him. He's fat.
- 那你干嘛不去和他比？ - 我會和他比的，他現在太胖了
Good. Snap out the teeth. This is your big comeback, right?
好，別光說不干，你光榮復出的機會來了
- That's what Alice wants. - You knocked out Joey Ferrell.
- 那才是愛麗絲想要的 - 你打敗過喬伊﹒費雷爾
All right. I knocked out Joey Ferrell, OK? But the guy is a middleweight.
好，我打敗過喬伊﹒費雷爾 好，但他是中量級選手
I'm a welterweight. They didn't have a fuckin' heavyweight to throw in there?
我是次中量級的 他們干嗎不直接找他媽的重量級的來打？
Tell him, Dicky. He can do it, right? He can do anything.
告訴他，迪奇，他能做到的，對吧？ 他無所不能
Oh, yeah, Alice. No problem.
好，愛麗絲，沒問題
You watch from the outside, pal.
你現在可是在一邊旁觀了，兄弟
Ladies and gentlemen, Mike "Machine Gun" Mungin!
女士們先生們 有請“機關槍”邁克﹒曼津
Holy shit.
該死
Hey, hey, look. That's Sugar Ray Leonard.
嘿，看，那是舒格﹒雷﹒倫納德
Hey, Ray. Ray, Ray, Ray.
嘿，雷，雷
- Hey, Ray! Sugar Ray! Over here! - Dicky.
- 嘿，雷！舒格﹒雷！這里！ - 迪奇
Come on, look at the size of that guy.
看看那家伙的塊頭
- Holy shit. - Yeah, holy shit.
- 靠 - 是，靠啊
That guy's no welterweight.
那家伙肯定不是次中量級的
All right, Mick. We'll have to run the first few rounds, tire him out.
好了，米奇，我們要開始第一局了，拖垮他
He did not just get off the fuckin' couch.
他肯定沒有疏于訓練
If he did, I'm gonna buy a couch like that.
他如果是，那我也要買個那樣的訓練設備
I don't care who that guy is...
我不在乎那家伙是誰
Look at me. You're Micky Ward.
看著我，你是米奇﹒沃德
Micky Ward, fighting a last-minute replacement from Philadelphia.
米奇﹒沃德，對陣 最后一刻頂替上場的費城拳手
Ward, thrown around by a much bigger man!
沃德，被比他強壯得多的選手 打得無招架之力！
- Punches, smashing Ward back! - Jab!
- 几記重拳猛攻沃德 - 刺拳！
Now it's big Mike...
現在是大塊頭邁克…
Ward goes down! Ward goes down!
沃德倒地了！沃德倒地了！
- Come on! Come on! ...four, five...
起來！起來！四！五！
...six...
六
Micky Ward's a fuckin' bum! Get rid of this dude!
米奇﹒沃德真差勁！快滾出這場子！
- Shut up! - Motherfucker!
- 閉嘴！ - 操你媽！
Mungin didn't even know he'd be fighting today.
曼津甚至不知道他今天要比賽
Hey, you, back off!
嘿，你，退后！
Come on! No, no, no, Mick!
上啊！不，不，米奇！
Ward, a respected fighter.
沃德是一位令人尊敬的拳擊手
You hope this mismatch doesn't hurt his confidence.
希望這場級別失衡的比賽 不會打擊到他的自信
- You're a loser!
- 你個廢物！ - 廢物！
Ladies and gentlemen,
女士們先生們
before we get started, a lot of people have been asking
在我們開始之前，很多人問我們
about the big night of boxing on November 4.
11月4號的拳擊界榮耀之夜
Three world championship bouts...
三場重要的世界級冠軍賽
Ray! Hey, Ray! Ray!
雷！嘿，雷！
- Hey! - Dicky. How you doin', man?
- 嘿 - 迪奇，你過得怎樣？
- How are ya? - All right, man.
- 你呢？ - 還好
He's 165 pounds. ESPN screwed us. You know?
他重165磅，ESPN騙慘我們了
- The guy was huge. - Hey. You know, I...
- 那家伙塊頭是很大 - 嘿，我…
I knocked Ray down.
我打倒了雷
I look like shit, but I knocked Ray down.
雖然我看起來很差勁，但我打敗過雷
Hey, let me buy you guys a drink. All right?
讓我請你們喝酒吧，好吧？
- Want a cold one? - No, no, no.
- 要冰的？ - 不，不
I got to leave. I got a plane to catch. Next time, right?
我得走了，我得趕飛機，下次吧
Hey, Ray, wait, wait. HBO's makin' a movie on me. You know?
嘿，雷，等下 HBO正給我拍電影，你知道嗎？
Can I call ya?
我能給你打電話嗎？
I'm gonna get a fight, and I just like ya to be there for old time's sakes.
我馬上要比賽了 看在老交情的份上，我希望你去看
- You commentate or something. - What's the movie about?
- 你可以解說什么的 - 關于什么的電影？
My comeback. Right?
我的復出
- Call me. Love you, brother. - I'll call ya.
- 給我打電話，愛你，兄弟 - 我會的
You don't be a stranger!
老交情了！
He's funny, "What's the movie about?"
他問得太搞笑了“電影的主題是什么？”
What's that?
那是怎么了？
You can do better. You're too good a boxer, I've watched you.
你能做得更好 你是個優秀拳擊手，我一直看著你
- Are you going to the hospital? - What is that?
- 你要去醫院嗎？ - 怎么回事？
- They said I need to get stitches. - Mick, nobody's got heart like you.
- 他們說我要去縫几針 - 米奇，沒人比你更努力
You're a very talented fighter, but you're not getting the right fights.
你是個非常有天分的拳擊手 但你選錯了對手
- It's killing your chances. - What's he talking to Mike Toma for?
- 這扼殺了你的機會 - 他和邁克﹒托馬說什么？
- I don't know, Dick. - I want to give you a real shot.
- 我不知道 - 我想給你一次真正的機會
I want you to come with me. I want to pay you to train with my guys.
我想讓你跟著我 我會出錢讓你和我的人一起訓練
- Where? - Las Vegas.
- 哪里？ - 拉斯維加斯
Do it right and make one last run at this thing before it's too late.
現在還為時未晚，做出正確的決定 再最后搏一把
What about my brother?
我哥哥呢？
With all due respect, he's too much trouble.
恕我直言，他是個麻煩
You owe it to yourself to come to Vegas.
你最好自己決定來維加斯
Come on, Mick, what has Dicky done for you?
想想，米奇，迪奇對你做了什么？
He got you into fights, he lets you get beat, like you did tonight.
他讓你去比賽，讓你像今晚一樣被打敗
You shouldn't have been in that fight. Eighteen pounds, think of it that way.
你明白的 你根本不應該參加那種比賽，差18磅
You should've given it up.
你本該放棄這場比賽的
Sit down in the car there. Come on, you.
安分在車里坐著，行了吧，你
- Sit the hell down. - A little more Scotch for Mama.
- 該死的坐著別動 - 再給媽媽來點舒格蘭威士忌
There you go. Nice and easy. Don't hurt yourself coming back.
給你，慢慢喝，爭取安全到家
- Will ya, ya old broad ya? - Oh, my God.
- 好嗎，老婆子？ - 天吶
Oh, my God, that Sugar Ray, he's a beautiful man, isn't he?
噢，天啊，那個舒格﹒雷 他是個美男子，是吧？
He didn't recognize me straight away.
他沒有馬上認出我
You seen the way he was looking at me?
你看到他盯著我看的樣子了嗎？
He's a good guy. I like him, I like him.
他是個好人，我喜歡他
I seen him on ringside, he was so happy seeing me and Mick together.
我在拳擊場看見他的 他很高興看見我和米奇一起
He's all about family, that guy. Loves to see a family stick together.
他家庭觀很重 喜歡看見一家人緊緊團結在一起
Mick, what'd Mike Toma want with you last night?
米奇，邁克﹒托馬昨晚找你干嘛？
- He wants to train me in Vegas. - What?
- 他想在維加斯訓練我 - 什么？
You can't trust that guy, Micky. He ain't family, you know?
你不能相信那家伙，米奇 他不是家人，明白嗎？
You don't know him. He say anything about me? Did he say I could come?
你又不了解他，他有說到我嗎？ 他說我可以去嗎？
He didn't mention you.
他沒有提到你
What are you gonna do in Vegas without your brother?
沒了你哥哥，你去維加斯干嘛？
That guy just wants to use you like a piece of toilet paper.
那家伙就是想利用你，像廁紙一樣用完就扔
What are you gonna do in Vegas without Dicky? Without your family?
迪奇不在，家人不在，你去維加斯做什么？
- I know, that's what I told him. - You told him that, right?
- 我明白，我跟他這么說了 - 你真跟他這么說了？
Yeah, I told him. I said that I needed to be with my family in Lowell.
真的，我跟他這么說了 我說我要和我家人一起住在洛厄爾
That's right. Nothing wrong with that.
說得好，一點沒錯
Sugar Ray said call him. We're gonna call him, baby.
舒格﹒雷讓我們打電話給他 我們要打給他，甜心
That's right.
沒錯
You guys can spar a little, right?
你們倆可以對練一會兒，對吧？
Where are they?
他們在哪？
- There's my champ! - Daddy's home!
- 我的冠軍寶貝！ - 老爸回來了！
- Daddy's home! Daddy's home! - Give him a big hug.
- 老爸回來了！老爸回來了！ - 熊抱下
I love you!
我愛你！
Thank you.
謝謝
Your face hurting you, sweetheart?
你臉疼嗎，寶貝？
No? 'Cause it's killing me. Come on.
還好？ 我很心疼
Did Uncle Micky win the fight?
米奇叔叔贏了嗎？
No, Micky didn't win this time. Not this time.
不，米奇叔叔這次還沒贏
Hey, Mick, you take care. I'll call you tomorrow.
嘿，米奇，保重，我明天再聯系你
Cheer up. We'll get you another fight.
振作起來，我們會再給你安排比賽的
I don't know, Ma. I don't think I wanna do this no more.
我心里很亂，媽，我不想再比賽了
What don't you wanna do no more?
什么叫不想比了？
Just, I don't wanna do it anymore.
就是不愿再干這個了
- What are you? - Hey, Mick, ESPN screwed us.
- 你說什么？ - 嘿，米奇，ESPN耍了我們
All right? They owe us. We'll get another fight. You'll heal up.
他們欠我們的 我們還會有比賽的，你會痊愈的
- It's gonna be OK. - Yeah, listen to your brother.
- 一切都會好起來的 - 對，聽你哥哥的
They owe us big-time, sweetheart.
他們欠我們太多了，親愛的
Maybe they'll even do Dicky's comeback fight.
也許他們還會拍迪奇的復出賽
What do you think?
你說呢？
Oh, come on, cheer up. You take a little soak when you get home,
噢，振作點，回家洗個澡放松一下
have a day or two to think about it. I'll find you a better fight.
花一兩天時間好好想想 我會幫你找更好的比賽
A much better fight. I'm gonna talk to them.
好得多的比賽，我會再找他們談
- For Chrissakes, Alice. - What?
- 看在上帝份上，愛麗絲 - 怎么了？
He's been through the ringer. Leave him alone, will ya?
他輸了比賽很難過，讓他一個人靜靜
What are you talking about?
你在說些什么呢？
Let him get some time to himself. He just got finished.
讓他一個人待會，他才剛打完比賽
- What's your fuckin' problem? - Come on.
- 你有病吧？ - 想想吧
Where's Micky? Is Micky not gonna come in?
米奇在哪？他不進來嗎？
No, he's not coming in. He needs to get back and get some rest.
是的，他不進來了，他得回去好好休息
Come on, let's go inside.
我們先進屋吧
No. He's gonna go rest. He's all grumpy.
不，他應該休息，他太暴躁了
He's beat up, he's a little embarrassed, I think.
我認為他受到了打擊，而且覺得很尷尬
Look at him. Have you even seen him?
看看他，你看到他了？
Who is it?
誰？
I saw the shade move.
我看見你掀窗帘了
Micky, the shade is still moving.
米奇，窗帘還在動
I saw you come to the window, I know you're in there.
我看見你走近窗戶了，我知道你在家
Least you can do is open up this door and tell me to my face
再怎么說你也要開門，當面給我解釋清楚
why you didn't call me yesterday.
昨天為什么不給我打電話
Why'd you stand me up last night?
昨晚為什么放我鴿子？
I started to call. I was gonna call, but... I just couldn't.
我想打的 但我不能…
'Cause you lost the fight?
因為你輸了比賽？
Maybe, yeah. 'Cause I lost the fight.
也許吧，因為我輸了比賽
How'd you know my house, anyway?
你怎么知道我家地址的？
I asked my brother.
我問我哥了
Your thing's coming off.
你的紗布掉了
I mean your other thing.
是另一邊
You got any tape?
有膠布嗎？
Did the black Jewish guy do this to you?
是那個猶太黑人把你打成這樣的嗎？
I didn't get to fight the black Jewish guy.
我沒能和他打
You didn't get to go head, body, head?
你沒能運用你的“頭，身體，頭”戰朮？
Saoul Mamby got the flu. Guy who took his place had 20 pounds on me.
曼比患了流感，代他上場的人比我重20磅
I never should've fought him.
我就不該和他打
- Why did you? - Nobody would've got paid.
- 為什么改變主意？ - 不打沒有錢拿
Everybody said I could've beat him.
大家都說我可以擊敗他
Who's everybody?
大家指誰？
My mother, my brother.
我媽，我哥
So are you gonna take me to dinner and a movie, or what?
你還准備和我一起吃晚飯看電影嗎？
- Hey.
- 嘿
- You look great. - Thank you.
- 你真漂亮 - 謝謝
Got a nice house, too.
你家真精致
It's an apartment building. There's five of 'em in there.
只是個公寓，住了五人
One of my old roommates lives in one.
我以前的一個室友和我住一起
Roommate? What, were you in the Army?
室友？你當過兵？
- College. - College. Wow.
- 大學 - 大學，哇
Yeah, a lot of good it did me. I work in a bar.
什么都沒學到，我在酒吧工作
Well, you seem to enjoy it. You're very popular down there.
你貌似很喜歡你的工作，在那很受歡迎
Yeah, popular. I gotta get out of there.
受歡迎，我還想離開那里
If I don't drink while I'm working, I'll fuckin' kill myself.
我上班如果沒酒喝，還不如自殺
- What college? - URI. Full boat.
- 你讀哪所大學？ - 羅得島大學，獲得過體育全額獎
Full boat's a scholarship, right?
那是獎學金，對嗎？
- Yeah. - For what?
- 對 - 獎勵什么？
- I was a high jumper. - High jumper? You gotta be kidding me.
- 我曾經是跳高運動員 - 跳高？你沒開玩笑吧
Fuck you. I was good. I was New England champ. I cleared 5' 8".
去你的，我很厲害，是新英格蘭冠軍 我的記錄是5英尺8英寸
- Wow. - Never graduated. I partied too hard.
- 哇 - 可惜沒能畢業，玩得太瘋了
You?
你？
What are we doing in Richie Rich Lexington?
我們到萊克星頓的 里奇﹒瑞奇（著名時裝）區干嘛？
You come to this theater a lot?
你常來這個劇院嗎？
Yeah, it's a good theater. They got good movies here.
嗯，這里很不錯，電影也很棒
- Yeah, like what? - Belli Epi-que.
- 比如？ - 《美好鏈帶》
I think it's Belle Epic. It's "epic." Belle Epic.
我認為是《美好臉蛋》 是“臉蛋”，《美好臉蛋》
Belle Epoque. The New York Times loved it.
是《美好年代》（1992） 紐約時報很鐘愛的片子
Well, I never heard of it.
我從來沒聽過
Where'd you hear about it? The New York Times?
你從哪知道的？紐約時報？
No, a guy from work.
不，同事告訴我的
And the cinematography is supposed to be gorgeous.
影片的拍攝技朮應該很棒
Oh, cool.
酷
Thank you.
謝謝
That's the movie you wanted to see?
那就是你想看的電影？
There wasn't even any good sex in it.
連性都沒有涉及
Had to read the whole fuckin' movie. Fuckin' subtitled.
還他媽的不得不看字幕理解，該死的字幕
And some guy from a road crew recommended it to you?
修路的同事給你推荐的這個？
A fuckin' subtitled movie?
帶字幕的電影？
What's going on?
怎么了？
What's going on? You got a girlfriend or something? You hiding me from her?
怎么了？你已經有女朋友了？你瞞著我？
I don't have a girlfriend, all right?
我真沒女朋友
I... I like you.
我喜歡你
I came here 'cause I don't wanna show my face in Lowell.
我帶你來這 因為我不想讓洛厄爾的人認出我
I told everybody I was gonna win that fight and get back on track.
我跟所有人都說能贏那場比賽，重振雄風
I told my daughter I was gonna get a bigger apartment so she can move in.
我跟我女兒說我要買一套大點的公寓 她就能搬進來
You don't think I wanted to call you?
你真以為我不想給你打電話嗎？
I was embarrassed. I mean... I'm sick of being a fuckin' disappointment. I...
我覺得很丟臉，我受夠了總讓別人失望
You really think your family's looking out for you?
你真覺得你家人為你考慮了嗎？
Don't say that about my family.
別那樣說我家人
What else can I say after what you told me?
聽了你告訴我的，我還能說什么？
I mean, look at your face.
看看你的臉
Look at you.
看看你現在的樣子
Bullshit, Lou. I'm not gonna stop callin' till you make this right
狗屁，盧，你不糾正這事我就一直打你電話
and give us a fight that's fair.
還有幫我們找場公平的比賽
My boy could've got killed last time.
我兒子上次差點被打死
Yeah, like what?
你有什么新消息？
Just don't tell me he just got off the fuckin' couch.
別又告訴我那人疏于訓練
He's coming off a loss?
剛輸了一場？
Sounds very interesting. I'll get back to you.
非常有意思，回頭再打給你
We got a great opportunity here.
絕好機會來了
We gotta go find Micky.
快去找米奇
Nobody's seen him for like three weeks.
貌似大概三個禮拜沒人看到他了
Jesus.
天吶
Used to be Dicky we couldn't find, now it's both of them?
以前只是找不到迪奇 現在他們兄弟倆都找不到了？
Ma, I think he's with that girl from the bar.
媽，我猜他是和那個酒吧女郎在一起
- What girl? - It's that fuckin' girl, Charlene.
- 什么女的？ - 就是那個娘們，沙琳
That's who he's with. That girl from the bar.
那就是和他在一起的那個酒吧女郎
George was all fuckin' eager for them to get together.
喬治正迫不及待地撮合他倆呢
I heard she's into three-ways.
據說她喜歡3P
- Yeah, with other girls. - Yeah, like one of those MTV girls.
- 沒錯，和其他女孩一起 - 對，她很像一個MTV女郎
MTV... What are you talking about?
MTV女郎是什么意思？
Wild.
很狂
She acts all fuckin' superior 'cause she went to college.
覺得她念過大學就高人一等
You girls just go find your brother, Micky.
你們趕緊去把米奇找回來
Tell him we've got important business to discuss.
告訴他我們有很重要的事和他商量
I've gotta go find Dicky.
我得去找迪奇
Dicky!
迪奇！
Hey, Ma, there's nothing in there. I just...
嘿，媽，那里什么事都沒發生，我只是…
It was just some friends I was seeing, you know?
只是見些朋友
Don't worry about it, Ma.
別擔心，媽媽
I was just helping 'em out, you know?
我只是在幫他們
Hey, Alice...
嘿，愛麗絲…
Alice...
愛麗絲…
I started a joke
我開了個玩笑
Which started the whole world cryin'
卻使全世界泣不成聲
Oh, if only I'd seen
如果我早明白
That the joke was on me
我才是被嘲笑的那個人
I started to cry
我開始哭泣
Which started the whole world laughin'
卻使全世界放聲大笑
Oh, if only I'd seen
如果我早明白
That the joke was on me
我才是被嘲笑的那個人
I looked at the skies
我仰望天空
Runnin'my hands over my eyes
雙手在眼前舞動
And I fell out of bed
從床上跌落
Hurting my head...
傷到了頭
So you're Beaver and you're Red Bear.
你是海狸，你是紅熊
- Red Beard. - She's Red Dog, and that's Beaver.
- 紅胡子 - 她是紅狗，那才是海狸
You're Red Dog. You're Beaver.
你是紅狗，你是海狸
- Yeah, don't use those names. - It's just for family.
- 不要這樣叫我們 - 只有家人才能
Be nice.
禮貌點
Don't use the nicknames.
別叫綽號
I don't think I'll fuckin' call 'em anything.
我不認為我是真把他們當動物叫的
Speaking of family...
說到家人…
Hello.
你好
- Alice, this is Charlene. - Hi.
- 愛麗絲，這是沙琳 - 你好
I've heard a lot about you.
我聽到很多關于你的消息
Really? I've heard a lot about you, too.
是嗎？我也聽到很多關于你的消息
- What's that supposed to mean? - Same thing you meant.
- 那是什么意思？ - 和你一樣的意思
Can we just sit down and talk about business?
我們能坐下來商量一下正事嗎？
I got you another fight, Mick. Just like I said I would.
我又幫你聯系了一場比賽，米奇 就像我承諾過的
Lou Gold and ESPN made it right.
盧﹒勾爾德和ESPN談好了
Just like I told you. Joe Belinc. Six weeks. The Foxwoods.
就像我跟你說的，喬﹒貝林 六周后，康州快活大賭場
Kid's like, you know, ten and eight, he's nothin'.
那小子大概只有118磅，無足輕重
You know? And they're gonna pay us 20 grand.
而且他們會付我們兩萬酬金
- Seventeen-five, Dick. - Seventeen-five.
- 17500美元，迪克 - 17500美元
Which is still... good money, Mick.
還是很大一筆收入，米奇
Yeah.
嗯
Yeah, that's good, Dick. I'm just,
嗯，是不錯，迪克，我只是
you know, trying to figure out what's best for me.
想弄清楚最適合我發展的道路
Like what?
比如？
What's best for you, sweetheart?
什么最適合你，親愛的？
Come on, Mick, I thought you'd be more excited.
米奇，我原以為你會更興奮的
Why ain't you more excited? It's a good fight, good money.
你為什么顯得興味索然呢？ 公平的比賽，丰厚的收入
I got tough with Lou Gold. Told him he owes us.
我對盧的態度很強硬，告訴他他欠我們的
Yeah, I know, Ma. I don't want things going the way they've been going.
我知道，媽，只是我不想再像從前那樣
Mick, that last fight, it was unfair. That was unfair.
米奇，上次那場，不公平，一點都不公平
- And we ain't gonna repeat that. Right? - No, not on your life.
- 我們不會再重蹈覆轍了 - 這輩子都不會了
No, but... It's just you in the ring.
但上拳擊台的只有你
Yeah, I know it's me in the ring.
我知道是我在拳台上打
But I don't like the way things have been going here.
但我不喜歡現在的運作方式
- Where? - Here. This. Us. Lowell.
- 哪里？ - 這里，拳擊，我們一家，洛厄爾
The whole routine.
全部的慣例
- George, stay out of it. - You're doing all the talking.
- 喬治，你別插手 - 都是你在說
Let him talk. Listen.
讓他說，你們聽著
- I'm askin' him. - You're tellin' him.
- 我在問他 - 你只是在頤指氣使
- Listen. - Stay out of it.
- 聽著 - 別管
Don't tell me to stay out of it.
別這么跟我說話
Mick, what's the problem?
米奇，你有什么問題？
- The problems. - What problems?
- 很多問題 - 比如？
- Problems... - Like what?
- 問題… - 到底是什么？
Like, maybe you not showing up on time to train.
比如你在訓練時不按時出現
Like maybe him having to come find you in a crack house
也許是他不得不去可卡因屋找你
when you're supposed to be at the airport.
當你該去機場的時候
I'm sorry. I don't know who you are, or why you're talking.
對不起，我不知道你是誰 有什么資格這樣說
I'm Charlene. We just met.
我是沙琳，剛見過
We're together. Do we need to do this again? Hi, I'm Charlene.
我們明明在一起，還需要我再介紹一遍嗎？ 你好，我是沙琳
Hey, we're together!
嘿，我們在一起！
What are you gonna do, Mick? Listen to some MTV girl who works in a bar?
你會怎么做，米奇？ 聽某些在酒吧工作的MTV女郎的話？
What's she know about boxing?
關于拳擊她懂什么？
I know that going to Vegas and gettin' paid to train year-round
我知道去維加斯接受全年帶薪訓練
sounds a hell of a lot better than what you got him doing here.
聽起來比你讓他做的好十萬八千里
You gonna let her talk like that to your mother?
你就這樣讓她和你媽說話？
Come on, Micky.
說話啊，米奇
I told you, we're together. This is my girlfriend. I want her here.
我說過了，我倆在一起 這是我女朋友，我希望她在這里
I have done everything... everything I could for you, Micky.
我做了一切所有我能為你做的，米奇
- This MTV girl comes along... - Stop calling me an MTV girl,
- 這個MTV女郎來了后 - 別再那么叫我
whatever the fuck that means.
不管那是什么意思
- Skank. - It's wild.
- 粗俗下流 - 很狂
I've been doing this over 15 years. She comes in, disrespects me.
我干這行已經十五年多了 而她一來就頂撞我
She don't mean no disrespect, OK?
她不想這樣的，知道嗎？
I had a chance to get paid to train year-round, year-round, OK?
之前我有全年帶薪訓練的機會，是全年
That's all she's talking about.
她只是說這事而已
I would hope that you guys could appreciate that.
我希望你們能理解這對我意味著什么
I know what you're talking about. All right? I could've had that.
我明白你的意思 我曾經也可能有過這種機會
You know? I had... I had opportunities, like maybe you're gonna have.
知道嗎？我當時也有像你這樣的機會
Now... You want money so you can train year-round? Yeah?
現在，你接受全年訓練需要錢？對嗎？
I'll get you money so you can train year-round.
我會給你錢，這樣你就能全年訓練了
- You? How? - Yeah, I'll do it. Trust me.
- 你？怎么做？ - 我來搞定，相信我
Hey, trust me. All right? Done.
相信我，好嗎？這事先到這
All right? Charlene? Yeah? Everyone?
好嗎？沙琳？好嗎？大家？
So, you put in $200, right?
如果你投入200美元
Then you get ten other people to put in 200...
然后你讓另外10個人每人投入200美元
...and you got your 2,000.
這樣你就有2000美元了
- Everybody give you $200? - No, not everybody, just ten of you.
- 每個人都給你200美元？ - 不是，不是每個人，十個就夠了
Ten lucky ones.
10個幸運的人
You rip us off.
你是在敲詐我們
No, no, I'm giving you an opportunity.
不，我是在給你機會
You give me $200.
你給我200美元
No, you get that from ten other people who you offer the opportunity to.
不，是你給其他10個人提供機會 從他們那里拿錢
Right? You understand? No?
對吧？你懂了嗎？不懂？
He thinks you think Cambodian people are stupid.
他認為你把柬埔寨人都當傻子
I love Cambodian people. I mean, look at Karen.
我愛柬埔寨人民，看看凱倫
She's my girlfriend. She's beautiful. I love her.
她是我女朋友，她美極了，我愛她
You know, and Brian. We work on a road crew together.
布萊恩，我們一起在修路隊工作
- Well, not so much lately. - We work on a road crew together.
- 最近沒有經常在一起 - 我們一起在修路隊工作
You haven't been showing up, that's all I'm saying.
我只是說，你一直沒出現
This ain't an anti-Cambodian thing.
這不是和柬埔寨人敵對
White people do this to other white people.
白種人之間也這樣交流
- It's what makes the world go round. - Boo Boo, I don't think that's helping.
- 這是世界運行的規律 - 布布，你那么說沒用
I mean, this is... a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
這是一生僅有一次的機會
I mean, they didn't understand.
他們根本不懂
You know, I mean, they're practically my gang.
他們本來可以稱之為我的弟兄
Usually, they listen to what I say, but they just didn't understand
一般他們都會聽我說的 但這次他們就是不理解
the opportunity, you know, I was offering them.
我給他們提供的這個好機會
- What were we talking about? - Before you fought Sugar Ray.
- 我們說到哪了？ - 在你和舒格﹒雷比賽之前
Right, right, right. I mean, Sugar Ray was too much too soon.
對，對，舒格﹒雷 當時體格和速度上都比我強
You know, I needed to build up slow. You know, right?
我需要鍛煉體格慢慢趕上
What's this movie about, again?
這部電影的主題是什么？
I told you, it's about crack addiction.
我告訴過你，是關于毒癮
Showing what it really is so kids can see it for real.
用紀實手法反映，孩子們會更加警醒
Fuck.
靠
We gotta get Mick's money.
我要去給米奇弄錢了
Yes! That was awesome!
好！太棒了！
Go. Right now.
* 好時光，壞時刻，我都會經歷*
Go, go, go...
去，去
- Get out of the car! - Oh, shit!
- 滾下車來！ - 哦，靠！
Get out of the car, now! Move!
滾下車！滾下來！
Put your hands on the roof!
把手放在車頂！把手放在車頂！
- That's it! Empty your pockets! - Are you a cop?
- 就這樣！ 把兜里的東西掏出來！ - 你是警察嗎？
Go to the fuckin' sidewalk. Move! Fuckin' move! Don't turn around!
滾到人行道上去，動作快點！動作快點！不准轉身
Don't turn around! Gonna have to take your vehicle.
不准轉身！我們要征繳你的車
- How am I gonna get home? - That's your problem!
- 那我怎么回家？ - 自己想辦法！
Get us some rocks. How much we got here? Count it.
來點好東西！有多少錢？ 數一下
What the fuck?!
怎么了？！
That's the guy! He did it to me and he's doing it again!
就是他！他以前也這樣騙我！ 現在又干老本行了！
- Dicky, get on the ground, right now! - Get that fucking!
- 迪奇，趴在地上，現在！ - 操！什么運氣！
Ta-da! What do you think?
噠噠！你覺得怎樣？
Open the door! Trying to get off the fuckin' street!
開門！我要進去！
What the fuck! I'm trying to get off the fuckin' street!
他媽怎么回事！有人在追我！
Get your fuckin' hands off me!
把你的臭手拿開！
Did you hear me?!
聽不懂？！
You gotta see this! They're fuckin' up Dicky Eklund!
你得看看！他們在扁迪奇﹒埃克隆！
It's Dicky! It's Dicky Eklund. The cops are all over him.
是迪奇！是迪奇﹒埃克隆！那些警察在揍他
They're fuckin' punching him, they're beatin' him. He needs help!
他們用重拳、警棍打他，他需要幫助！
Stay here! Don't get up. Stay here!
別動！別起來，呆在這！
- Listen to him. You stay right here. - I gotta go.
- 聽他的， 你呆在這 - 我必須去
You better get back here. Are you fuckin' kidding me?
你最好坐在這里。你他媽開什么玩笑！
Hey, what the fuck? Come on, just put him in the car!
嘿，他媽什么事？讓他坐進車里！
You don't need to do that! Just put him in the car!
你不一定得打他！讓他坐進車里！
- Come on, just let him go! - You wanna get involved?
- 到底聽不聽，放開他！ - 你也想攪合進來？
Now you're involved!
現在你不能脫身了！
You're fuckin' up my brother! I'll kill you!
你他媽敢打我弟弟！我要殺了你！
He's a fighter! Break his fuckin' hands!
他是拳擊手！打斷他的手！
- Don't! - I didn't do nothing!
- 不！ - 我什么也沒做！
- Shut the fuck up.
- 給我他媽閉嘴
Move 'em out!
把他倆帶回警局！
Micky, your hand. Your hand.
米奇，你的手，你的手
Don't tell me to come on.
別告訴我手下留情
Back up yourself, for Chrissake.
看在上帝份上，安分點
Hey, separate cars, separate cells.
分車坐，分牢房
I don't want them making up some bullshit defense story.
我可不想聽到 他們編出什么狗屁正當自衛的借口
Come on, folks, time to go home. Let's go.
好了，大家都該回家了，散了吧
- No blankets. - Dicky!
- 沒有毯子！ - 迪奇！
What the fuck, man!
你他媽搞什么！
- Micky! - Jesus Christ.
- 米奇！ - 上帝
Don't get involved. You shouldn't get involved, sir.
別攪合進來，你別攪合進來，先生
Look at his hands.
看看他的手
Shit.
靠
Go home, folks. Good night!
各自回家吧，晚安！
Welcome back, Dicky. That's 27 arrests.
歡迎回來，迪奇，第27次被逮捕
Ward, one count of disturbing the peace,
沃德：一項擾亂治安指控
released on your own recognizance.
交具結書后釋放
Eklund, three counts of assault and battery on a police officer,
埃克隆：三項暴力襲警指控
two counts of resisting arrest, two counts of larceny from a person,
兩項拒捕指控，兩項盜竊指控
two counts of impersonating a police officer.
兩項假扮警官的指控
Bail set at $25,000. Case continued, two weeks from today.
保釋金25000美元，兩周后再次開庭
- Come on. - Judy, can I have the file three-57?
- 別這樣 - 朱迪，我需要第357號文件
I need a copy of the discovery reports as well.
還有調查報告的復印件
Mick, you're gonna say it was self-defense, right?
米奇，你會說是正當防衛，對吧？
- You did it to yourself, Dicky. - What?
- 你是自作自受，迪奇 - 什么？
You're gonna say it was self-defense, right?
你會說是正當防衛，對吧？
You came outside, you seen them beatin' on me, I didn't do nothin'.
你從里面出來 你看見他們打我了，我什么都沒做
Right? I was just waitin' outside like anybody? Mick, I was doing it for you!
我就是像其他人一樣在外面站著，米奇 我為了你才這么做
You did it for me? What, this?
為了我？讓我手傷成這樣？
Do me a favor, don't do fuckin' nothing for me no more, OK?
拜托，他媽什么都別再為我做了，好嗎？
I'm fuckin' done lyin' for you.
我再也不想幫你圓謊了
What are you gonna do without me?
沒有我你能干什么？
This isn't how it was meant to go down!
事情不是那樣的！
They should've just put me in the car!
他們本應該直接讓我進警車的！
Oh, Mick, come on! Mick!
米奇，幫我！米奇！
Dicky! Hey, what's up, Dicky?!
迪奇！嘿，怎么了？！
Hey, Eklund!
嘿，埃克隆！
Dicky!
迪奇！
Hey, you knocked out Sugar Ray!
嘿，你不是擊倒舒格﹒雷了！
Dicky, Dicky, Dicky...
迪奇，迪奇
Who is it?
誰？
I don't want to see you, Micky.
我不想見你，米奇
- Charlene... - I can't take it.
- 沙琳 - 我不能接受
I'm not gonna let you or your family drag me down.
我不想被你和你的家人拉下水
I'm quitting, Charlene, OK? I'm done fightin'.
我不干了，行嗎？我不做拳擊手了
I don't need it anymore.
再也不需要了
- That's fuckin' stupid. - What? Why?
- 真他媽愚蠢 - 什么？為什么？
Because it's sad that you let them take it away from you
因為你就讓他們奪走你的夢想 真是太悲哀了
with their stupid bullshit.
還是用他們愚蠢的方式
What else can I do, Charlene?
沙琳，我還能怎么做？
There's a lot you can do, Micky.
你有很多能做的，米奇
There's this guy that your dad wants you to meet.
你爸爸希望你去見一個人
You just don't think you can do it without Dicky.
可你覺得自己沒有迪奇什么都做不成
Charlene...
沙琳
Don't call.
別叫我
Come on.
別這樣
Don't call me, OK?
別再叫我了，好嗎？
Hey, Dicky, you hurtin', man?
嘿，迪奇，很難受嗎？
Poor fucker!
可憐的傻逼！
Hang in there, man!
忍著點，兄弟！
Go, Dicky!
上，迪奇！
Hey, Dicky!
嘿，迪奇！
Hey, keep it quiet!
嘿，安靜點！
Hey, Micky! Bring another bucket, huh?
嘿，米奇，再拿一桶來？
Good.
很好
And this Friday, an HBO original documentary.
本周五，HBO原創紀錄片
Right here in Lowell, Mass, the story of Dick Eklund,
為您講述在馬薩諸塞州洛厄爾 迪克﹒埃克隆的故事
a once-promising boxer who turned criminal...
昔日拳壇希望之星怎么淪為獄中囚
Oh, look who it is.
哦，看看誰來了
That's him. That's Dicky's brother.
那是迪奇的弟弟
- Hey, Micky. - Regular.
- 嘿，米奇 - 像往常一樣
- Hey, what's up, Mick? - Look who's here.
- 怎么，米克？ - 看看誰來了
- Good to see you, bro. - How you doing?
- 見到你很高興，兄弟 - 你好嗎？
How you feeling? How's the hand?
覺得怎么樣？手好些了嗎？
- It's gettin' there. - Looks better.
- 快好了 - 看起來好多了
Why don't you come down to the gym? And work out. If you want.
你怎么不去健身房做點鍛煉，如果你想的話
- Hey, you fat fuck, you're getting big. - Yeah, I know. I just...
- 你這胖家伙，更肥了 - 我知道，就是…
Been roofin' with my father, spending time with Kasie.
幫我爸整修屋頂，多花點時間陪陪凱西
Now I gotta worry about this movie on HBO tonight.
現在我擔心的今晚HBO的那部片子
What are yous looking at?
看什么看？
Movie's not about him. It's about his crazy brother.
電影又不是說他，是說的他那個瘋哥哥
I gotta go.
我得走了
- Come back to the gym, Mick. - Bye, Mick!
- 回健身房訓練吧，米奇 - 再見，米奇！
Don't go watch that crazy shit on TV, don't!
別用電視看那個屁片子，別看
Hollywood!
好萊塢！
Get a look! Get a look, all right!
你們看看！看看！
Going to Hollywood! Going to Hollywood, yeah!
進軍好萊塢！進軍好萊塢！
All right!
好了！
All right, get this started!
好了，把電視打開！
Lowell was the birthplace of the Industrial Revolution in America.
洛厄爾孕育了美國工業革命
Industrial Revolution... Lowell.
工業革命…，洛厄爾
I used to live over there. This town got good memories, right?
美國吸毒現象
- Check it out. - Fuck, yeah.
- 看看吧 - 靠，沒錯
- This house here, this white house? - Oh, yeah.
- 這里的那棟白色房子？ - 對
White, big fat guy. First time I got my crack, over here.
那棟很大的白房子 我第一次就是在這吸的可卡因
Did you ever know that? They smoke crack at the White House?
你知道他們在白房子里吸毒嗎？
White, black, Puerto Rican, everything.
白種人，黑種人，波多黎各人 各式各樣
The first time I did crack, or whatever, I was about 23
我第一次吸毒是大概23歲左右
and a friend of mine gave me a gram, or whatever.
一個朋友給了我一克左右
Fuck, I wish that'd never happened.
真希望這沒有發生
Before that, I'd been doing the Silver Mittens and stuff.
在那之前，我一直參加 銀手套少年拳擊賽和別的比賽
I was the only kid. I'd be 12... I was shit-faced.
我還是獨子的時候才12歲，有時會喝醉
I'll tell ya how crack works.
我會告訴你可卡因是怎么讓人成癮的
When it enters your lungs...
當它進入肺部，進入肺部
- I wanna watch, Daddy. - Oh, my God. No, sweetie.
- 我想看爸爸 - 哦，天吶，別
- You go back upstairs. - But I wanna watch Daddy on TV.
- 上樓去 - 可是我想看爸爸上電視
I know, baby. You can't watch Daddy right now, all right?
我知道，寶貝，但你現在不能看，好嗎？
You go back upstairs and go to bed, OK?
上樓去睡覺，好嗎？
OK, yeah, there's my boys right there. Check 'em out.
好，那是我的兄弟，看看他們
- What kind of snake's that? Python? - Yeah, check it out, man.
- 那是什么蛇？蟒蛇？ - 對，看看它
- It's not gonna bite me or something? - He's cool.
- 它不會咬我或是攻擊我嗎？ - 它很聽話
It's been a while. I'll take anything right now.
逗了它一會了，我來者不拒
I never thought I'd kiss a fuckin' snake.
我從沒想過自己會親一條蛇
I always dreamed about it...
頂多做做夢
Do a lot of shit when you're high, right?
興奮起來淨干些傻事，對吧？
Dicky... put Lowell on the map.
迪奇，使洛厄爾這個小城揚名
He knocked Sugar Ray Leonard down.
他打倒了舒格﹒雷﹒倫納德
Yeah, he knocked him down, but I don't think it was a knockdown.
對，他打敗了舒格﹒雷﹒倫納德 但我不認為那是有效擊倒
- I think he slipped. - He knocked him down.
- 我認為是雷滑倒了 - 他是打倒了雷
- He didn't slip. - He slipped.
- 雷沒有滑倒 - 他有
- Oh... and you're from Lowell. - Yeah, come on.
- 哦，你也是洛厄爾的 - 得了吧
- That's a fuckin' lie! - They said he's in trouble with drugs.
- 淨他媽的胡說！ - 他們說他是癮君子
What is this? Are you talking shit about the family?
你干嗎呢？你亂說家里的事了嗎？
- Oh, no, no, no... - I heard you say "Dicky, Micky..."
-哦，沒有，沒有 - 我聽到你說“迪奇，米奇”
We're not like that. This is not what Lowell is all about.
我們不是那樣的，那并不是洛厄爾的全部
I thought he could make a comeback
我以為他會光榮復出
- and make us proud, but he didn't. - I don't know what Dicky was thinking.
- 讓我們驕傲，但是他沒有 - 我不知道迪奇在想什么
Very disappointing, very disgusting.
真讓人失望,惡心
You brought the city of Lowell back 30 years. We're not happy.
你讓洛厄爾倒退了30年，我們很生氣
- Hello? - Jimmy?
- 你好？ - 吉米？
Hey, will you do me a favor? Make sure Kasie's not watching HBO?
嘿，你能幫我個忙嗎？ 現在別讓凱西看HBO行嗎？
Actually, we're watching it right now, Mick, but don't worry about it.
實際上，我們現在正在看，米奇 不過別擔心
I got it...
我會…
I want her to see it. Let her see who her uncle is.
我想讓她看看，讓她看看她叔叔是什么人
- What? - Who you are.
- 什么？ - 看清你是什么人
Who I am? What are you talking about?
我是什么人？你說什么呢？
- Kids need to know the truth, Mick. - Laurie, turn it off, please.
- 孩子需要知道真相，米奇 - 勞里，關掉電視，求你了
She does not need to see this. She doesn't need to see it.
她不需要看這個，她不需要
She's a kid.
她還是個孩子
When you smoke crack, you know...
當你吸食可卡因
... you feel so much lighter.
你會飄飄欲仙
You know, you feel young, like when everything was in front of you,
你會覺得自己很年輕，進入了仙境
everything was just...
一切都…
... it was in front of you, you know?
進入仙境了，你懂嗎？
And then...
然后
... it fades and you gotta get high again.
然后這種感覺消失了，你要再吸一次
Your part in the movie is gonna end with you going to jail.
由于你進監獄，你在電影里的角色也終結了
What about little Dicky? Who's gonna take care of him, huh?
那小迪奇呢？誰會照料他？
You guys can't talk to 'em?
你不能和他們說說嗎？
Oh, man...
哦，兄弟
Turn this shit off. Turn this off, all right?
把這破玩意關了，把它關了
Turn it off. Will you turn this off?
關掉它，幫下忙？
If you don't... I'm turning it fuckin' off.
你不關…，那我來關
Hey, hey, that is my life.
嘿，那是我的生活
- My movie night! - That's my fuckin' life out there.
- 我的電影夜！ - 那說的是我操蛋的生活
- I wanna watch this. I don't care. - I will fuck you up!
- 我想看，你的生活關我什么事 - 操你媽！
You fuckin' want some? Don't fuckin' try me.
你皮痒了？再惹我試試
I still fuckin' got it, OK?
我他媽有這權利，好吧？
You fuckin' want some?!
你想來几拳頭？！
That's my son there, and you're laughin' at him?!
我兒子在電視上，你卻嘲笑他？！
That's my son. He's crying. He needs me. And I'm fuckin' stuck in here?
那是我兒子，他在哭，他需要我 我卻被關在這鬼地方
But you know what? Dicky was a street kid.
但你知道嗎？迪奇曾是小混混
Micky, you watching this? What are they doing to us?
米奇，你在看嗎？他們怎么能這樣對我們？
Ma, I don't know what to tell you.
媽，我不知道該怎么說
You're pretending like you don't know what's going on.
你一直裝作什么都不知道
He's been doing this for years.
他這個樣子已經很多年了
Yeah, I know it's horrible, Ma, but...
是，媽媽，我知道很糟糕，但…
- What do you think? - You think they set him up?
- 你覺得呢？ - 他們陷害他？
What do you think he was doing?
你覺得他干了什么？
You know, gave him money, gave him drugs for the movie. Right?
是他們給他錢，給他毒品 讓他同意拍電影，對嗎？
Micky... Micky?
米奇…米奇？
Shit. Micky...
靠，米奇
- You got a new bag, huh? - Yup.
- 你換新沙袋了，是吧？ - 嗯
- New bracket, too?
- 新支架？ - 對
- What happened to the peanut? - I don't know.
- 那個花生形狀的怎么了？ - 不知道
It's like a beach ball.
現在這個像個沙灘球
- Mick. Sal Lonano. - Hey, Mick, how you doing?
- 米奇，薩爾瓦多﹒拉納羅 - 嘿，米奇，你好嗎？
You own a cab company, you're a good businessman, right?
你是計程車公司的老板，經營的不錯，是嗎？
- Yeah, he's very organized. - How's the hand?
- 他很精明 - 手怎么樣了？
It's good. You know, it's getting better. Stronger.
還不錯，感覺越來越好了，越來越有力了
Yeah, you know, I made a few calls already. I talked to Buddy Tags.
我已經打了好几個電話了 我還跟巴蒂﹒泰格斯談過
Said he can set up something local, something to start back with.
他說可以在本地給你安排一些比賽 可以讓你重振旗鼓
- Get your confidence back. - That's it.
- 重拾信心 - 就是那個
You gotta get your confidence back. That's all.
你必須把你的自信找回來 這是目前最重要的
Your dad wants Sal to manage ya, and he wants me to train ya.
你父親想要讓薩爾做你的經紀人 還想讓我來訓練你
But I'll only do it on one condition.
但有一個前提
- No crazy-time nonsense. - It's how it's gotta be.
- 就是一定要按規矩辦 - 就是這樣
- No Dicky. No Alice.
- 迪奇和愛麗絲不參與
I get it, I get it. I'm good, I understand.
我懂，懂了，沒關系，我明白
- Look, I appreciate the opportunity. - I can't take the bullshit, Mick.
- 我會珍惜這個機會 - 不能再胡來了，米奇
- No offense, Georgie. - None taken.
- 沒有冒犯的意思，喬治 - 沒事
I'm gonna be the one who gets his balls cut off, anyway.
反正我會在愛麗絲那邊死得很慘
- Yeah. You laugh. - You...
- 嗯，你滿意了 - 你
...fuckin' traitor! - What are you doing?
- 你個叛徒！ - 你在干什么？
What the hell's the matter with you?! Come on! The pans hurt!
你他媽的這是怎么了？！ 搞什么！鍋砸的很疼！
Do they hurt?! I hope it hurts!
傷到你了？那才是我想要的！
- Sal Lonano is a good man! - A good man?!
- 薩爾瓦多﹒拉納羅是個好人！ - 好人？！
He's a legitimate businessman, for Chrissakes!
天吶，他是一個正當的生意人
- Legitimate businessman? - Yes. What?
- 正當的生意人？ - 是，怎么？
Oh, my God, you know what that sounds like?
我的天，你知道那聽起來像什么嗎？
- He's a crook, George! - He owns a taxi cab company!
- 他是一個騙子，喬治！ - 他擁有一家出租車公司！
- He's organized! - Oh, my God. He's a cab driver.
- 他很精明 - 他只是個開出租車的
He knows everything about boxing, right?
他很懂拳擊，好嗎？
I don't think so! He's gonna steal your son's money and rob him blind!
鬼才那么想！ 他會偷走你兒子的錢，把他洗劫一空
Why would you think that? Why would you even think that?
你為什么這么想？怎么會那么想呢？
- Why can't you trust anybody with? - I know people.
- 你為什么這么多疑？ - 我懂人性
I know, George, you think I don't know anything, but I know people.
我知道，喬治 你以為我什么都不懂，但我懂人性
- I know you know people. - And that Sal Lonano
- 我知道你懂人性… - 那個叫薩爾瓦多的長著個大鷹鉤鼻的家伙
We haven't made one dollar with these kids!
我們還沒有通過這些孩子們掙到一分錢！
- You betrayed me! - Oh, bullshit, I betrayed you.
- 你背叛了我！ - 扯淡，我背叛了你
- You always react the same way. - He's a fuckin' crook!
- 你每次都那么說 - 他是一個該死的騙子！
What's Micky supposed to do? Dicky's in jail!
米奇該怎么辦呢？迪奇還在蹲監獄呢
We're not talking about his trainer, sweetheart!
我們說的不是他的教練，親愛的
We're talking about his manager, that's me!
我們說的是他的經紀人，就是我
But, Mom, maybe Micky should try something different!
但，媽媽，也許米奇該嘗試些不同的東西
What are you doing opening your mouth in my kitchen?
誰准許你在我的廚房里說話了？
- You owe me $200. - I said I was gonna pay you next week.
- 你欠我200美元 - 我說過我下星期會給你的
I don't want another word outta you.
你給我閉嘴
That was last month you told me two weeks.
上個月你就告訴我兩個星期后還我
You take sides against me in my own house, you owe me money?
你還欠我錢，就敢在我的房子里面跟我作對？
And Ma's been great to Micky, Sherri.
媽媽對米奇一直都很好，謝里
Really, I mean, who's gonna look out for Micky better than his own mother?
真的，對待米奇 有誰能比他自己的母親對他更好？
It's that fuckin' girl, Charlene. We gotta get rid of her.
都怪那婊子，沙琳，我們要讓他離開米奇
Ma, we gotta get rid of her. It's that girl, Charlene. She gotta go.
媽，我們要讓他離開米奇 都是她，沙琳，她該走
You're gonna get Charlene involved?
你們還要把沙琳牽扯進來？
- Is that what you're telling me? - I know where she lives.
- 你們就在告訴我這個？ - 我知道她住哪
What are you pickin' on her for?
你們總喜歡找她岔干嘛？
She lives in that yellow house on Stevens Street.
她家就是斯蒂芬斯街那棟黃色的房子
I'm gonna go talk to Micky, sort this out for myself.
我要去跟米奇談談，把事情說清楚
Yeah, sure. You go handle it with your vigilantes. All of yous now.
對，當然了，你帶著你的“積極分子”去解決 你們現在都一起走
This is wrong, Alice!
別這么做，愛麗絲！
I got it!
我來開車門
Get outta my way! Get in the car!
滾開，上車！
Come on, come on, come on, come on!
快點，快點！
Get in the car.
上車
- Yeah, they're in there! - Up there on the second floor.
- 對，他們在里面！ - 就是二樓的那個房間
Micky!
米奇！
Where the hell are you? You up there? Come on down!
你該死的在哪？在上面？快下來
Where are you?
到底在哪？
Holy shit, Micky, your mother and your sisters are here.
靠，米奇，你媽跟你的姐妹們都來了
No, don't. Do not go out there. Please.
不，不，不要出去，求你了
No, I'm not hiding from your crazy fuckin' family.
我才不會逃避你那些混賬家人
Hi.
你們好
Well, well, well. Look at this.
哇，看看他們
Look at what?
看什么？
- Why you hiding from us, Micky? - He's not hiding.
- 你為什么要躲我們，米奇？ - 他沒有躲
Wasn't talking to you. I was talking to my son.
我沒跟你說話，我在跟我的兒子說話
What are you doing, Mickster?
你在干什么，米奇？
I'm right here. I ain't hiding from nobody, Alice.
我就在這兒，沒有躲任何人，愛麗絲
You're not helping yourself with your father's scumbag friend Lonano.
你讓你爸卑鄙的朋友拉納羅 給你安排比賽是自毀前程
What are you gonna do, turn your back on Dicky next?
你要怎么做？下一步扔下迪奇？
All we ever wanted for you was to be world champion.
我們一直以來都期盼你成為世界冠軍
Micky's a grown man. He can think for himself.
米奇已經是成年人了，他可以自己思考
- Shut your mouth. - Skank.
- 閉嘴 - 賤人
Don't call me skank. I'll rip that nasty hair right out of your fuckin' head.
再這么叫我 我會把你頭上的該死的頭發扯下來
I'm his mother. And his manager.
我是他的母親兼經紀人
You're not my manager anymore. And I'm not waiting for Dicky, OK?
你已經不再是我的經紀人了 我也不會等迪奇了，好嗎？
I'm not gettin' any younger.
我也老大不小了
Who's gonna look after you, sweetheart?
親愛的，誰會照顧你呢？
I mean, come on. I know you don't understand it, but I had nine kids
想想吧，我知道你不會明白的 但我有九個孩子
- and I love every one of you the same. - You got a funny way of showing it,
- 而且都深深愛著你們每一個 - 你已經用很可笑的方法証明了這點
letting him get beat up, letting him get his hand broken.
讓他被痛扁，讓他的手受傷
- You're crazy. - You fuckin' bar skank!
- 你瘋了 - 你這該死的酒吧婊子！
- What did I just say to you? - Don't put your hands on her...
- 我剛跟你說的什么？ - 別把你的手放在她的…
- Get off of me! - Stop it!
- 放開我！ - 停！
Let her go!
放開她！放開她！
- Fuck you, Charlene! - Fuck you!
- 操，沙琳！ - 操！
- Get the fuck outta here! Now! - Fuck you, Charlene!
- 你們他媽都給我滾！現在！ - 操，沙琳！
- Skank! - Micky...
- 賤人！ - 米奇
- Fuckin' bitch! - Oh, my God! Gail!
- 該死的賤人！ - 天吶！蓋爾！
What'd she do to your nose?
她對你的鼻子做了什么？
What is happenin'? What is happenin' to everybody?
發生什么事了？大家怎么了？
I don't understand, sweetheart.
我真不明白，親愛的
Why... Why do you think I spell my name with an E?
為什么你以為我的名字開頭多了一個E？
'Cause I don't.
我從來不這么說
- No-E Micky Ward. - Hey, somebody push the button.
- 沒有E﹒米奇﹒沃德 - 嘿，按下電梯
- Where we going? What's with the ring? - Ring's across the street.
- 我們去哪？拳擊場在哪？ - 拳擊場就在街對面
- The ring's across the street? - Yeah.
* 我就從此而來，我要重回正軌 *
Yeah, smaller venue. They got no dressin' rooms over there.
一個小場地，那里沒有更衣室
- Yeah, but... - Micky, It's just a start. Don't worry.
- 可是… - 這才剛剛開始，米奇，不要著急
Hey. Good luck.
嘿，祝你好運
That's it!
就是那樣！
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
對！對！
Visit for Dick Eklund.
有人探望迪奇﹒埃克隆
Dicky!
迪奇！
Eklund, you got a visitor!
埃克隆，你有訪客！
Heard you won a bunch of fights, Mick. That's good.
聽說你贏了好几場比賽了，米奇 干的不錯
I know you know what I been doing.
我知道你了解我在做什么
I'm sure Alice and everybody else told you.
愛麗絲和其他人肯定都跟你說過了
I just wanted to tell you to your face myself.
我只是想當面跟你說
I got new management. Mickey O'Keefe's my trainer now.
我請了一個新的經紀人 還有麥奇﹒奧基夫是我的教練
It's all good.
一切都進展的不錯
Yeah. They got you fightin' Alfonso Sanchez.
對，他們還幫你安排 跟阿方索﹒桑切斯打比賽了
- On HBO. - And you're proud of that?
- HBO直播 - 你很自豪吧？
- Fuckin' right. - HBO is invested in the Mexican.
- 太對了 - HBO一般投資墨西哥選手
I didn't think they were gonna be invested in me?
我原來想也不敢想他們會給我投資
- I got a shot. I'm gonna take it. - Wake up.
- 現在我的機會來了，我要好好把握 -  醒醒吧
They don't care if he kills you.
他們都不在乎你的生死
Mike Toma did it. He's using you, like a stepping-stone for Sanchez.
邁克﹒托馬是幕后主使，他在利用你 把你看做是桑切斯的墊腳石
- Why don't you see? - Oh, I see.
- 你為什么不明白？ - 我明白
How could I stand a chance without the great Dick Eklund in my corner, right?
沒有偉大的迪奇﹒埃克隆幫我 我怎么能錯過這樣一個機會，對嗎？
You didn't give a fuck if I got killed by Mungin.
我當初有可能會被曼津打死 但你一點都不在乎
Now all of a sudden you're worried Sanchez is gonna hurt me? Why?
現在你又突然擔心我會被桑切斯傷到 為什么？
'Cause you're stuck in here and can't be the center of attention no more?
因為你被關在這里 再也不能成為人們的焦點？
- You need it that bad? - I've seen this Mexican fight.
- 你就那么想成為中心？ - 我看過這個墨西哥拳手的比賽
He fights, hits, like a fuckin' mule, all right?
他擊打，沖撞，像騾子一樣強壯，好嗎？
Fifteen knockouts, undefeated. You crazy?
15場不敗戰績，你瘋了嗎？
And that taxi cab idiot, Lonano, he went right for it.
還有那個開出租車的笨蛋，拉納羅？ 這正是他一手策划的
He's a paper gangster, he's using you to steal money.
他不是一般的流氓，只在利用你大撈一把
Why can't you just shut up and be happy for me?
你為什么就不能把嘴閉上為我感到高興？
I spent the last ten years of my life in bad fights set up by you and Alice.
我把過去十年浪費在 你跟愛麗絲安排的垃圾比賽上
I finally got a good thing going for me
現在我終于熬出頭了
and you can't be fuckin' happy for me? Why?
為什么你他媽就不能為我感到高興？ 為什么？
What's your plan? How you gonna fight Sanchez?
你的策略呢？你打算怎么跟桑切斯過招？
- I ain't here to talk about that. - What's your plan?
- 我不打算在這討論 - 你的策略是什么？
- I am not here to talk about that.
- 我不是來談那個
Yes, you are.
你應該和我談這個
You watch the fight and you'll see the plan.
你看到比賽時就知道我的策略了
I can't watch it. They don't let us. It's too fuckin' violent. I mean...
我看不到，他們不讓我們看 拳擊比賽太暴力了
Two minutes, Dicky.
還有兩分鐘，迪奇
They'll let us watch a stupid documentary about crack,
他們讓我們看一個關于毒品的愚蠢記錄片
but I can't watch my own brother fighting, you know?
但我卻看不到自己兄弟的比賽
Hey... Mick, what is it?
嘿，米奇，是什么？
You scared? You embarrassed because you don't even have a plan?
你害怕了？ 還是你根本沒有計划所以你感到難堪？
I'm your brother. Just tell me.
我是你的哥哥，告訴我吧
Are you gonna shit on it no matter what I say?
無論我說什么你都不會亂評論嗎？
I'm not gonna shit on it. Just tell me.
不會亂評論，告訴我吧
Go toe-to-toe. Overhand right in the middle rounds.
近戰，在中間几局用右手大擺拳
He's weak against the overhand right.
他在防守右手大擺拳方面很弱
Who came up with that? Fatty fuck O'Keefe?
誰的主意？胖子奧基夫？
Fuck you, Dicky.
靠，迪奇
You gotta run against this guy. Let him punch himself out.
你要跟他打拉鋸戰，直到他把體力耗光
Take him to the body, right? Get inside.
攻擊他的身體，貼近他
Switch stances like you're gonna work his right, hit him on the left.
不停的變換姿勢，右虛左實
You ain't me. All right? You can't be me.
你不是我，好嗎？你也成為不了我
- Careful. Switch outside... - You had a hard enough time
- 小心，在外場變換姿勢的時候… - 你連自己的事都管不好
being you when you had your fuckin' chance,
當你有機會的時候
and that's why you're in here. I'll fight Sanchez the way I fight.
這也是你會在這里的原因 我會用我自己的方式跟桑切斯較量的
I'm talking about the way you fight, you moron!
我跟你說的就是你該怎么打，你這笨蛋！
Yeah, you know I'm right! He knows I'm right. All right.
你們知道我是對的，他也知道我是對的
He knows I'm right.
他知道我是對的
Ward's record: 29 wins, seven losses so far, 20 KOs.
沃德的記錄：目前29勝7敗，20次有效擊倒
He's been a little better since he refocused himself on the sport,
他回歸這項運動后，表現有所改善
as JB pointed out.
就像JB所述的那樣
Now, here's Ward's opponent, Alfonso Sanchez, out of Tijuana, Mexico.
現在出場的是沃德的對手 阿方索﹒桑切斯，來自提華納，墨西哥
You see the record: 16 wins, 15 KOs, eight first-round KOs.
他的戰績是：16勝，15次有效擊倒 8次首輪有效擊倒
There's Mike Toma, the promoter of the fight,
這是麥克﹒托馬，這次比賽的承辦人
who has a lot invested in Sanchez.
他在桑切斯身上投入了很多資金
And he says that Sanchez is
他說桑切斯是
one of the most talented young prospects in the sport of boxing.
拳擊界最有潛力的天才年輕選手之一
This is really one of the saddest kinds of fights in boxing.
這真是拳擊界中最悲劇的比賽之一
- Get out of the corner! - Micky Ward is 31 years old,
- 別躲在角落！ - 米奇﹒沃德31歲了
he's here because he needs the money, he's taking a beating...
因為他需要錢，所以來到這里 他在被動挨打
And my point is that he doesn't really have to sit here
我覺得他真的不能停在那里
and take this beating. He can do something about it.
一直被動挨打了，他應該主動進攻
Which is what? Have his corner throw in the towel?
他能做什么呢？承認陷入困境直接認輸？
- Or fight back. - Get back.
- 還是回擊 - 退回去
You can see his power.
你可以看到他的力量
Every time he hits Ward, he backs him up.
每次他打沃德的時候，后者都被打得向后退
How about taking points away from him?
就這么拿分太簡單了？
Larry, unless the referee does, you can't.
拉里，除非裁判做出指示 否則你不能上去
The referee should just go ahead and stop this fight.
裁判應該直接終止比賽
He knows that Micky doesn't want to be here. I wouldn't even make...
他知道米奇不想再比賽了，我甚至沒有做…
He's fightin' scared, Dick.
他打的很膽小，迪克
Runnin' away, not hittin' back.
只是躲開，沒有還擊
Oh, Jesus. He's gonna get hurt.
哦，天啊，這樣下去他會受傷的
Doing that same old shit.
還是那老一套戰略
They never seen such an embarrassing performance.
他們從未看過這么尷尬的表現
He's doing what I told him, Ma. He's doing what I told him.
他在做我教他的，媽媽，他在做我教他的
Don't worry about it.
別擔心，他在做我教他的
Micky Ward, showing nothing but respect.
米奇﹒沃德除了被挨打外什么都沒干
What are you runnin' around for? Stop running around!
你在逃避什么？不要跑來跑去
Shut the fuck up, Sal! Shut the fuck up!
他媽閉嘴，薩爾！閉嘴！
I don't know what you're doing, Micky. Want to fuckin' tell me?
我不懂你在干嘛，米奇，想跟我談談？
'Cause I don't know what you're doing.
因為我都不知道你在干嘛
We have lost all five rounds, is that what you want?
我們都已經輸了前面的5輪了 這是你想要的？
Dreadful. This is dreadful, dreadful stuff.
很可怕，太可怕了
You gotta show me something soon, Mick, or I'm gonna stop the fight.
你必須趕快做點什么，米奇 不然我就要終止比賽了
Now they're gonna stop the fight, Micky.
他們要終止比賽了，米奇
He's gotta go inside, Ma.
他會貼上去的，媽
He's gotta take it to the body. He's gotta.
他會攻擊對方的身體，他知道的
Come on, get your punches up...
你要把拳頭舉起來…
- Don't stop the fight. - They're gonna stop this fight.
- 不要終止比賽 - 他們要終止比賽了
Then you gotta do something, baby.
你必須做點什么，親愛的
That's not what we talked about, Micky.
那不是我們談過的，米奇
We had a plan and you're not doing it. Now, let's go.
我們計划好的，但你沒有按計划做 現在上場
All right, Micky.
好，米奇
You've lost the first five rounds. What's the next strategy gonna be?
你已經輸掉前五輪了，下一步策略是什么？
Double right hand by Sanchez, then a triple left hook.
桑切斯的兩次右手攻擊，緊接著三記左勾拳
A couple of the left hooks landed flush on the cheek of Micky Ward.
這几記左勾拳在米奇臉上留下了几道紅印
Ward tying Sanchez up.
沃德試著迎上桑切斯
Very curious performance by Micky Ward.
沃德的表現讓人很好奇
Come on, Micky, come on!
上啊，米奇，上！
Ward seems... trying to land one big shot
沃德似乎是想嘗試一次致命一擊
to change Sanchez's mind...
來擊倒桑切斯
And he's beginning to open up.
桑切斯開始放手一搏了
Taking advantage of more and more opportunities to get close to Ward
抓住更多機會靠近沃德
and throw against a fighter...
全力去攻擊這個拳擊手…
Time!
時間到！
...who's not defending himself by punching.
沃德不出拳來自衛
Sanchez is gonna try to end this fight.
桑切斯可能想直接結束這場比賽了
- What are you doing? Come on! - That's it.
- 你在干什么？上啊 - 對
Good boy!
好小子！
He's down on an uppercut!
他被一記上勾拳擊倒了！
- Nicely thrown left uppercut inside. ...three, four, five...
- 漂亮的內側左手上勾拳 - 3，4，5
And right after Ward threw a pretty good right hand.
就在在沃德剛打出一記不錯的右手攻擊之后
Mick, you all right? Come to me. Come to me.
米奇，你還好嗎？到這來，到這來
This is a fight that should be stopped.
這場鬧劇該結束了
Come on, head, body, head.
上啊，用“頭，身體，頭”戰朮
This is not professional.
這不是職業賽
That's exactly what I'm saying.
說的一點沒錯
- Punch him! You gotta punch! - Someone should pay me to watch this.
- 打他！ 打他！ - 我來看真得有人給我錢
Come on, man! Head, body, head!
上，兄弟！頭，身體，頭！
That was a good body shot by Ward.
沃德打出漂亮的腹部一擊
That was good. Maybe it'll turn him around.
打得不錯，也許他要扭轉局勢了
Maybe. I'm talking about if I...
也許，我說的是如果我…
Sanchez drops like he's shot! Oh, my God!
桑切斯像遭受了槍擊，倒在了地上！ 哦，天吶！
The most unlikely knockout you have ever seen.
前所未有不可思議的致勝擊倒
That was a kidney shot, the kind of kidney shot...
這拳擊中了腎臟，這種攻擊腎臟的拳
...nine, ten!
9，10！
I still don't believe what I just saw.
剛剛看到的還是讓我難以置信
Oh, Micky won!
哦，米奇贏了！
Now, did Micky Ward just make idiots of us all
現在，難道米奇耍了我們？
with a spectacular piece of strategy? Take another look. Amazing.
用驚人的戰朮？看看回放，太精彩了
A brilliant win in the career of Micky Ward out of Lowell, Mass.
這是來自馬塞諸塞州洛厄爾的米奇﹒沃德 職業生涯中的重大勝利
Unbelievable defeat at the hands of Micky Ward,
米奇用難以置信的擊敗手法
who had all but given away the first half-dozen rounds of the bout.
在白白讓出回合前六局后
I think what Micky did was he recognized
我認為米奇做的是意識到了
that he'd hurt the guy with the body shot.
他可以通過身體一擊給對手致命傷害
Micky's a better fighter than that to not be runnin' from that guy like that.
米奇采用的戰朮比和對手硬碰硬好得多
Theater of the unexpected.
充滿未知的舞台
Hey, you never know what can happen, right?
嘿，你永遠猜不到會發生什么，對吧？
Never give up in this game, right? Never give up.
永不言棄，對吧？永不言棄
You can't make it up, folks.
你們不能講和，大家得明白
You hear what he said?
你聽到他說的了？
He said, "You can't give up in this game."
他說“你不能在比賽中放棄”
Well, maybe Micky Ward heard me say you should stop this fight
也許米奇﹒沃德聽到我說他應該終止比賽
and he went out and stopped it.
然后他就直接發力終止了
- Right there. Right there. - Yeah! I can't believe it.
- 那邊，那邊 - 對！我還是不能相信
I'm lookin' over, and I'm thinkin' to myself like they were thinkin':
我環顧周圍，我覺得跟他們想的一樣
This thing is over.
這場比賽玩完了
But I tell you what, if you looked at the commentators,
但你知道嗎，如果看看評論員
they started to take their headsets off before he was even counted out.
他還沒被判輸，他們就開始把耳機摘掉了
They just wanted to get out of there.
他們都想從直播室出去了
Mick, Mick. I just spoke to Mike Toma.
米奇，米奇，我剛剛和邁克﹒托馬談了
- He told me something very interesting. - Holy shit, what?
- 他說了件非常有意思的事 - 靠，是什么？
He just told me,
他告訴我
had Sanchez won tonight, he would've gotten the title shot.
如果桑切斯今晚贏了 他就可以參加頭銜賽了
- Holy Christ, that's beautiful. - Why? Why is that beautiful?
- 天吶，那太好了 - 為什么？為什么會那么好？
- A title shot. Mick gets the shot. - Micky gets the shot!
- 頭銜賽，米奇可以參加頭銜賽了 - 米奇可以參加頭銜賽了！
- Are you kidding me? - Are you sure about that?
- 你不是在開玩笑？ - 確定嗎？
I just spoke to the guy. Mike! Come here, Mike. Look, tell these guys.
我剛和那家伙聊過，邁克！ 到這來，告訴這些人
- Hey, Mike Toma. Thank you. - Congratulations.
- 嘿，邁克﹒托馬，謝謝 - 祝賀你
You're not a stepping stone anymore. I always knew you had the talent.
你再也不是墊腳石了 我一直都知道你有天賦
That was a hell of a strategy, wearing him down and taking it to the body.
戰朮真他媽絕了！ 消耗他的體力，然后給他身體致勝一擊
Thirty years in the business, I'd never seen a knockout like that.
干這行30年，我從沒見過那樣的致勝擊倒
Larry Merchant was writing your obituary,
拉里﹒ 默切特正在給你寫訃告呢
and Sanchez drops like he's shot with a gun.
然后桑切斯就像中槍似的倒下了
Where'd you get that?
你怎么想到的？
That's the first thing my brother taught me.
那是我哥哥教我的第一件事
Tap 'em to the head, ding 'em to the body.
頭部輕擊，把致命一擊留給身體
- That's a hell of a body shot. - Thank you.
- 真是出色的身體一擊 - 謝謝
- You ready for a title shot? - I ain't gettin' no younger.
- 你准備好要參加頭銜賽了嗎？ - 我現在感覺又年輕了！
Thanks, Mr. Toma. Thank you.
謝謝，托馬先生，謝謝
He's ready. You're ready, aren't ya?
他准備好了，你准備好了，對嗎？
Shea Neary in London for the title.
和倫敦的西爾﹒內瑞爭拳王頭銜
Are you kidding, we got some celebrating to do.
你開玩笑嗎？我們得慶祝慶祝
- Yeah, I think so. - Thank you so much.
- 對 - 太謝謝了
- Gonna have a great champ in my boy. - Thank you, Mr. Toma.
- 我兒子要拿到偉大的拳王頭銜了 - 謝謝，托馬先生
It's what your brother would've always wanted.
那是你哥哥夢寐以求的
He's not even gonna be there.
他不會到場的
- Hey! - Daddy!
- 嘿！ - 爸爸！
- Come here, buddy. - Daddy, Daddy!
- 到這來，伙計 - 爸爸，爸爸！
Good to see you!
見到你太好了！
That's a good hug! That's a good hug! Yeah!
擁抱太棒了！擁抱太棒了！好！
- Sweetheart. - Hey, Ma.
- 親愛的 - 嘿，媽
Oh, you look so good. Oh, my God.
噢，天吶， 你看上去狀態很不錯
- You have clean teeth. - I do! Look at my teeth!
- 你牙齒變白了！ - 是啊！看我的牙！
I got new teeth. Everything.
我換了新牙，什么都煥然一新
How you think I look?
你覺得我看起來怎么樣？
- Good. - Yeah?
- 不錯 - 嗯？
Cake and more cake.
蛋糕和更多的蛋糕
- Ice cream? - Ice cream and cake.
- 冰激凌？ - 冰激凌和蛋糕
Ice cream and cake and cake. Right?
冰激凌和蛋糕、蛋糕，是嗎？
Ice cream, cake and cake. Ice cream, cake and cake...
冰激凌和蛋糕、蛋糕
Quacka!
哇！
Ma.
媽
- They gave you some new teeth, huh? - Yeah.
- 他們給你換牙了，哈？ - 是
Hey, Georgie. What, they let you outta the house now?
嘿，喬治，現在他們把你趕出房子了？
- Yeah. - Lettin' him outta the house, Ma?
- 對 - 把你趕出房子，媽？
Hey, look, I want you to meet Sal Lonano.
嘿，聽著，我想讓你見見薩爾﹒拉納羅
How you doing, Dicky?
過得怎么樣，迪奇？
Let's spar.
我們打一場
Hey, Charlene.
嘿，沙琳
Welcome back!
歡迎回來！
It's supposed to be a surprise. You're late.
本該是驚喜的，你們遲到了
Mick, I can't even tell you, being in this smelly-ass locker room. You know?
米奇，我自己都不知道 是不是期待著回到這間臭氣熏天的更衣室
Being back with you, this is what got me through.
和你一起打拳，這才能讓我撐過來
- You look good. Your eyes are clear. - Yeah. You know...
- 你看上去不錯，你的眼神更清明了 - 嗯，你要知道…
...Alice says prison might've been the best thing for me.
愛麗絲說也許蹲監獄是對我最好的安排
Got me clean. Got me clear. Up here.
讓我煥然一新，讓我頭腦清楚
It's a beautiful thing, Dick.
那樣很好，迪奇
- I gotta talk to you about something. - Yeah.
- 我有些事要和你談談 - 好
Look at this locker. The old locker.
看看這柜子，還是原來的柜子
I love it. Fuckin' love it.
我愛這柜子，真他媽愛
I made a promise to them I wouldn't work with you again.
我答應他們不再跟你合作了
I had to. After everything that happened, I'm sorry.
發生了這么多事后，我只能這么辦，抱歉
You stickin' to that?
你非要這樣嗎？
I'm glad you're back. You look good.
我很高興你回來了，你狀態很不錯
I don't know what else to say.
我不知道還能說什么了
- Mick, you fuckin' kidding me? - No, I'm not.
- 米奇，你跟我開玩笑嗎？ - 沒有
- Oh, hey, Mick. - Come on, come on!
- 嘿，米奇！ - 過來！
You gotta... Ma. You gotta do this at home. Please?
你們得…，媽，請回家再弄吧
What are you talkin' about? What's the matter?
你在說什么？怎么了？
Mom, please?
求你了？
All right, girls. Let's pack it up.
好，女孩們，打包走
I know. We'll see him at home.
我知道，我們會在家里見到他
- What the hell? - Would you please pack it up?
- 他媽怎么了？ - 你不能好好打包？
- Why? - Let's get it put away.
- 為什么？ - 讓我這么說
If that's what Micky wants, we're gonna put it away.
如果米奇想我們走，我們就走
- There's your brother. - Dicky...
- 你們的哥哥來了 - 迪奇…
- How ya doing? - Micky?
- 你們怎么樣？ - 米奇？
That's nice. That's nice.
太漂亮了，很不錯
We've been working on it for two weeks.
我們准備了兩個星期了
Sherri, come on, stop it.
謝里，干嘛呢，別哭了
All right, girls, come on, let's go home.
好吧，女孩們，咱們回家吧
It's not the time to do this, obviously. Come on.
顯然現在不是慶祝的時候
You stay here. What the hell's going on?
你呆在這，到底他媽怎么了？
- What's going on? - We ain't gonna work together.
- 出什么事了？ - 我們不會再一起打拳了
He don't want me to work with him.
他不想我和他一起工作
What're you talking about?
你說什么？
That's not right.
這不對
Micky never would've won Sanchez without Dicky.
沒有迪奇的話，米奇根本贏不了桑切斯
That's fuckin' bullshit! Take it back!
他媽的胡扯！收回你的話！
Hey, hey, hey, hey. Don't you fuckin' talk to my mother that way.
嘿，嘿，你他媽的別這么跟我媽說話
- Fuck you!
- 靠！
Take 'em home.
帶他們回去
Why don't you ask Micky?
你怎么不問問米奇？
If we're gonna train, they gotta go.
我們要訓練了，他們該走了
They gotta go, Mick, come on.
他們得走，米奇，你知道的
Ask him, George. Ask him if he would've won Sanchez without his brother?
問他，喬治，你問他要是沒他哥哥 能贏桑切斯嗎？
Hey, take him outside, all right?
嘿，把他帶出去，好嗎？
No, I wouldn't have won Sanchez if it wasn't for Dicky.
要不是有迪奇的話，我贏不了桑切斯
How can you say that to O'Keefe?
你怎么能對奧基夫說這種話？
Because it's true.
因為這是事實
I went with that game plan, it wasn't working.
我一開始按照我們制定的方案比賽 不起作用
So I went back to what I learned with Dicky.
所以我又按照迪奇教我的做了
And I wouldn't have won without you, either, O'Keefe, OK?
奧基夫，沒有你的指導我也贏不了，好嗎？
I mean, you know that. We worked hard. You got me ready.
我是說，你知道的，我們努力訓練 你讓我准備充分
You got your confidence and your focus from O'Keefe,
是奧基夫讓你重拾自信和重心
and from Sal and your father and from me.
還有薩爾，你父親和我
- Dicky's a junk bag. - Hey.
- 迪奇只是個癮君子 - 嘿
He's a junk bag!
他只是個癮君子！
- Fuck you, Charlene. - Fuck you.
- 操你，沙琳 - 操你才對
- I'm eight months sober. - Oh, yeah,
- 我有8個月不沾毒品了 - 是嗎
and I'm sure you're gonna need something now that you're out.
那我肯定你既然出獄了 你一定要從米奇身上拿別的東西了
"Oh, my back. Oh, my back."
“噢，我的背！噢，我的背出毛病了！”
- Fuck you always picking on me for? - No, fuck you!
- 你他媽干嗎一直找我的岔？ - 不，操你！
And what about O'Keefe? We're in the same boat.
那奧基夫呢？我們都訓練過米奇
One day at a fucking time, right, O'Keefe? You know what I mean?
曾几何時，對吧，奧基夫，你懂的
What, it's all right for him to be here?
為什么他都可以在這待著
Why am I the fuckin' problem? I'm his blood, I'm his family!
為什么我就不行了？ 我是他的兄弟，是他的家人
- You are the problem! - I'm the one fighting, OK?
- 你知道自己是個麻煩！ - 我才是上拳台的那個
Not you, not you, and not you.
不是你，不是你，也不是你
- I know what I need. - And you need Dicky?
- 我知道我需要什么 - 你需要迪奇？
I want Dicky back.
我想迪奇回來
And I want you, Charlene. And I want O'Keefe.
我需要你，沙琳，我也需要奧基夫
I want my family. What's wrong with that?
我需要我的家人，這有什么錯嗎？
It's not the deal we made, baby.
我們說好不行的，寶貝
She's right, Micky. That's not the deal.
她說得對，米奇，我們約好的
It wasn't the deal. Come on, you can't do this to us.
拜托，你不能這樣對我們
- You sound like them now. - I sound like them now?
- 你現在跟他們一個口氣 - 現在我跟他們一個口氣？
- Yeah, you sound like them. - You sound like them.
- 對 - 你才是和他們一個口氣
How could I do this to you? "You can't do that to us.
我怎么能如此對你？“你不能這么對我們
He can't do that to us." You sound like them.
他不能這么對我們”你就像他們
You should fuckin' listen to yourself.
你他媽該自我反省下
You sound like them and maybe this is where you belong.
你跟他們一個口氣，也許你們本來就是一家
That's the way you love him?
你就是這樣愛他的？
- Charlene! - Come on!
- 沙琳！ - 別這樣
- You wanted your brother? Good luck. - O'Keefe, come on.
- 你想要你哥哥回來？祝你好運 - 奧基夫，別這樣
- Mickey.
- 米克
Come on, everything happens for a reason.
別這樣，事出有因
You know? Maybe it's for the best. God has a plan.
你知道嗎？也許這樣最好，主自有安排
Wanna spar with your brother?
想和你哥切磋下嗎？
Dick Eklund, pride of Lowell!
迪奇﹒埃克隆，洛厄爾之驕傲
Watching that for years, huh?
那場比賽看了很多年了，哈？
Micky, Micky!
米奇，米奇！
Whoa, hey! What the hell are you doing?
哇，嘿！你該死的在干嘛？
Micky!
米奇！
- Daddy! Daddy, Daddy! - For crying out loud!
- 爸爸！爸爸！ - 我的天啊！
Take that baby out of here.
把孩子帶出去
I told you take him away ten minutes ago!
我十分鐘前就告訴你把他帶走了！
Sweetheart, you all right? You OK? Your back?
寶貝，你沒事吧？你還好吧？你的背沒事？
What are you doing? What's the matter with you?
你在干嘛？瘋了？
Can this be my fight, Alice? Just once?
是我要比賽，愛麗絲，哪怕一次
Maybe just this one time not for Dicky?
哪怕就一次，不是為了迪奇？
I know you think he's coming back.
我知道你覺得他要重振雄風
He's 40 years old and doesn't have a tooth in his head
可他都40歲了，嘴里的牙都不齊全了
- that's his fuckin' own. - I'll go fuckin' ten rounds.
- 連一顆自己的都沒 - 我還可以打十回合
Let your brother talk for a minute here, all right?
讓你弟弟把話說完，好嗎？
- What are you sayin', sweetheart? - I'm Shea Neary...
- 你想說什么，寶貝？ - 我是西爾﹒內瑞
Shut up before I bust your fuckin' head open, Dicky.
閉嘴，否則我打爆你的頭，迪奇
- Hey, hey... - What're you gonna do? I'm Shea Neary.
- 嘿，嘿 - 你想干嘛？我就是西爾﹒內瑞
You want me to bust your fuckin' head open?
你想我把你的頭打開花嗎？
Come on, come on! George, please!
勸一下，喬治，做點什么！
- Dicky! - Please! What are you saying?
- 迪奇！ - 你說什么？
- Tell me what you're saying. - This is supposed to be my fight.
- 告訴我你要說什么 - 這應該是我的比賽
This is my shot at a title. I won't get another one after this.
是我參加頭銜賽的機會 以后我再不會有機會了
- Am I being selfish? - No.
- 我很自私嗎？ - 不
Am I saying, "Micky, Micky, Micky?" You know what? If I am, I'm sorry.
我說過“米奇，米奇？” 你知道嗎，如果我說過，抱歉
I thought I was fightin' for the championship.
我認為是我為了冠軍賽而奮斗
And I thought you were my mother, too.
我還認為你也是我媽媽
I am your mother.
我是你媽媽
Yeah, Ma.
對，媽
Mick, I'm sorry. I had no idea you felt like that, all right?
米奇，抱歉，我不知道你有這種感受，好嗎？
If I made mistakes, I'm gonna be better.
如果是我的錯，我一定會改正的
I don't wanna hurt you. I am so sorry. I'm sorry.
我不想傷害你，我很抱歉
Dicky!
迪奇！
Stay with him.
陪著他
Dicky... Dicky!
迪奇…迪奇！
- Dicky! - Gotta do something.
- 迪奇！ - 我有事要做
Dicky, wait, come on!
迪奇，等等，拜托！
- Micky wants you! I want you! - I gotta do something.
- 米奇需要你，我需要你 - 我有事要做
I know what that means. Don't do this!
我知道你的意思，別那么做！
Hey, Chan.
嘿，陳
- What's going on? - Hey, Dicky.
- 你們好嗎？ - 嘿，迪奇
Hey, Dicky's back!
嘿，迪奇回來了
Look at you!
看看你！
What's up, my boy? How you doing? Good to see you, man.
還好嗎，小子？你呢？見到你真好，兄弟
- You look good. Welcome back. - Yeah, you're looking good.
- 你氣色不錯 歡迎回來 - 你看上去好極了
- Great. - Good to see ya.
- 太好了 - 見到你太好了
- Welcome home. - Hi, honey.
- 歡迎回家 - 嗨，親愛的
What's up, man? You're looking good.
還好嗎，伙計？你看上去不錯
- Wanna head upstairs? - Dicky's back.
- 上樓待一會？ - 迪奇回來了
- Hi, Dicky. We're gonna party. - Go upstairs, man?
- 嘿，迪奇，我們要好好慶祝下 - 上樓去？
- Go upstairs, take a while? - We missed you!
- 上樓待會？ - 我們想死你了！
- Let's go, buddy. - Come on, Dicky.
- 走吧，兄弟 - 來，迪奇
- Make for a little party for you... - Hey, come back.
- 給你辦個小派對 - 嘿，回來
- What the fuck's that all about? - What the hell was that?
- 就那么走了？ - 那算什么？
Charlene? It's Dicky.
沙琳？我是迪奇
Get off my porch, you piece of shit.
從我門廊滾開，你這個垃圾
How fuckin' dare you...
你還敢按…
... cocksucker...
混蛋
... fuckin'...
靠
You're a fuckin' asshole, Dicky.
你個混球，迪奇
I want you off my fuckin' porch!
我要你該死的滾開！
Why don't you just fuckin' come down here and talk to me?
為什么你不你直接下來和我當面說？
Such an asshole, coming to my fucking house. You piece of shit!
你這混蛋，到我家來，垃圾！
- Standing on my porch... - Charlene...
- 站在我家門廊… - 沙琳
It's not fuckin' lady-like to be shoutin' in the street like this.
街罵是婊子才干的
You're such a fuckin' cocksucker coming over here.
你這個來這搗亂的混蛋！
- Please? - Oh, yeah, you think I fuckin' care?
- 求你了？ - 哦，是嗎？你以為我他媽在乎？
- Come on, just fuckin'... - Get off my fuckin' porch, Dicky!
- 下來，開門… - 從我門口滾走，迪奇！
Would you just fuckin' come down here... and talk to me?
你難道就不能下來和我談談？
What kind of dog is that? Is that a Cocker Spaniel?
這狗什么品種的？是英國可卡犬嗎？
All right, I know you can't fuckin' stand me.
好吧，我知道你討厭我
Really, what makes you say that?
是嗎，你憑什么這么說？
I ain't got no use for you, either. All right? But my brother loves ya.
因為我也知道自己以前很混，但我弟弟愛你
And you can't just run away because of me.
你不能因為我而離開他
He don't deserve that. All right?
他不該承受那些，知道嗎？
So I will quit if you want me to quit.
所以如果你希望我退出，我就退出
- You're full of shit. - I swear to God.
- 鬼才信 - 我發誓
I will quit if it means you'll come back, all right?
如果你回來，我就退出，好嗎？
But I want you to think about something.
但我希望你能考慮一下
Micky has a chance to do something that I never did.
米奇有機會去做我從未做過的事情
That in my time, I never had.
在我這個打拳的時候，沒有得到冠軍
"Oh, yeah, my big chance was with Sugar Ray Leonard.
哦，對，我最大的成功 就是和舒格﹒雷﹒倫納德對打
I'm so great. I'm the pride of fuckin' Lowell.
我太偉大了，我是他媽洛厄爾之驕傲
Oh, yeah, I fought Sugar Ray Leonard." I've heard it.
對，我打敗了舒格﹒雷”我已經聽煩了
I came here to make things right.
我是來糾正錯誤的
- OK, let's make things right. - Yeah.
- 好 - 嗯
Number one: You didn't knock down Sugar Ray Leonard. He tripped.
第一，你根本沒有打敗舒格﹒雷 他自己絆倒的
I was in the ring. Don't you think I know what really happened that day?
我當時就在拳擊台 你以為我不知道那天發生了什么嗎？
All right? What have you ever done with your life?
是嗎？你這輩子都干了什么？
- I like my life. - Yeah, what you ever done with it?
- 我愛我的生活 - 是嗎？那你奮斗過么？
- I like my life now, Dicky. - What have you done with your life?
- 我喜歡現在的生活，迪奇 - 你這輩子都干了什么？
You're a college dropout, Charlene.
你只是個輟學生，沙琳
You're just a little bar girl. Your life sucks.
你只不過是個酒吧女服務生 你的生活糟糕透了
All right. I drank too much.
好吧，我承認我酗酒
I worked in a lot of bars.
我在很多酒吧工作過
And I ruined a lot of opportunities, but I'm trying to do something better here.
我錯失了很多機會，但是在這里我想做更好
- And so is Micky. - And so am I.
- 米奇也是 - 我也是
And he needs me. You heard him. And I know he needs you.
他需要我，你親耳聽到的 而我知道他也需要你
What is that blue shit on your arm?
你胳膊上那藍色的玩意兒是什么？
It's icing.
糖霜
OK. I'll see ya in Micky's corner. Otherwise, go fuck yourself.
我們米奇那見，不然你就滾一邊去
- It's a deal. - All right? It's a deal.
- 好 - 說定了
We worked it out for you. Ask her.
我們倆和解了，問她
Good. Go get O'Keefe back, too.
很好，去把奧基夫也找來
I will.
我會的
Hey, Mick...
嘿，米奇
You think I knocked down Sugar Ray Leonard?
你覺得我是把舒格﹒雷有效擊倒嗎？
Went ten rounds. One of the best ever and he couldn't hurt you.
你打了十個回合 是最好的戰朮而他卻對你束手無策
You were my hero.
你是我的英雄
I was.
曾經是
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
You are?
真的？
There's a press conference downstairs.
樓下有個新聞發布會
Come on, let's go.
來吧，我們走
Spot of tea, mate!
端好茶，伙計！
Neary: Ten stone... six pound.
內瑞：十英石（170磅），再加6磅
Ward: Ten stone... six pound.
沃德：十英石，再加6磅
Hey, Micky, Micky Ward! We have a question over here.
嘿，米奇，米奇﹒沃德！我們有個問題
- How you been training? - I train, I train hard.
- 你一直怎么訓練的？ - 訓練，努力訓練
Shea's 22 and 0. He's never been knocked down.
西爾是22戰全勝，從沒被擊倒過
- That's gonna change tomorrow. - In fact, we expected
- 明天就不會那樣了 - 實際上我們期待
a much better fighter.
一個更出色的拳擊手
I'm just grateful to be here and have the opportunity.
我很感激能有機會坐在這里
Thank you guys for the shot.
謝謝大家的提問
Shea, who do you respect as a fighter? And who would you like to fight next?
西爾，你認為誰才算個拳擊手 下場比賽你想挑戰誰
I plan on moving right through Micky Ward tomorrow.
我想明天直接擊倒米奇﹒沃德
Moving on to other great fighters, like Gatti.
挑戰更厲害的選手，比如加迪
Yeah, I believe Gatti and I would make a great match.
我相信我和加迪才是實力旗鼓相當
Are you scared, Mr. Ward?
你害怕嗎，沃德先生？
And now, ladies and gentlemen, 12 rounds of boxing
現在，女士們先生們，世界拳擊聯盟
for the WBU Welterweight Championship of the World!
十二回合制次重量級拳擊手冠軍爭霸賽 正式開始！
I can't see!
我看不到了！
Here I go again on my own
* 我再次獨自出征 *
Goin' down the only road I've ever known
* 走著自己唯一知道的道路 *
Like a drifter I was born to walk alone
* 像流浪者，我生而獨行 *
- Hey, fellas, let's go. - I made up my mind
- 嘿，伙計們，出發了 - * 我已決定 *
I ain't wasting no more time
* 絕無躊躇 *
Here I go again on my own
* 我再次獨自出征 *
Going down the only road I've ever known
* 走著自己唯一知道的道路 *
Like a drifter I was born to walk alone
* 像流浪者，我生而獨行 *
Don't listen to 'em, Mick.
別聽他們的，米奇
I made up my mind
* 我已決定 *
I ain't wasting no more time...
* 絕無躊躇 *
And there is Micky Ward of Lowell, Massachusetts,
現在上場的是來自 馬薩諸塞州洛厄爾的米奇﹒沃德
entering the ring. It's his first fight outside the United States.
這是他在海外的第一場比賽
Micky Ward: 30 wins, seven losses. He's gotten better recently, 20 KOs.
米奇﹒沃德：勝30場 敗7場 他最近狀態轉佳，20次擊倒對手
And now Ward awaits his opponent, Shea Neary.
現在沃德在等待他的對手西爾上場
Neary regards himself as the European Arturo Gatti.
西爾將自己比作歐洲的阿圖羅﹒加迪
Meaning that he is a head-on, high-contact fighter
意為他是一個正面出擊型選手
who throws 70 punches per round.
他一回合能出拳七十次
Neary's from Liverpool and should have
西爾來自利物浦，今晚應該會有
a huge following here tonight.
很多粉絲
Accompanied by Paint the Town Red by The Mahones.
他由瑪宏斯一家率領的“狂歡”團隊陪同
Neary is the current Welterweight Champion of the World.
西爾是現今世界次重量級拳擊比賽的冠軍
He is a very tough young man. Beyond dedicated.
他是一個堅韌不拔的年輕人 全身心投入拳擊
Lives a Spartan existence. And according to his promoters,
如同斯巴達勇士在世，據他的經紀人所說
does nothing but eat, drink, think, fantasize...
他的生活里除了吃、喝、思考
...dream of fighting.
就是對拳擊的夢想
Shea Neary has had 22 professional fights and won them all.
西爾22場職業拳賽全勝
Seventeen KOs.
17次有效擊倒
Come out when you hear the bell. Don't piss about. Shake hands.
鈴響時比賽開始，記得規則，請先握手
Both of ya... shake hands!
你們兩個，請先握手
As close as we just saw them in the middle of the ring,
正如我們在拳擊場中央看到的一樣
- forehead to forehead, - Did you see that?
- 他們針鋒相對 - 你看到了嗎？
That's how close we expect them to be for as long as this fight goes on.
我們也期待 他們呈現給我們一場精彩紛呈的拳擊比賽
Ward is a long ways from home.
沃德非本土作戰
Don't coast in a foreign country.
可能會水土不服
Well, the big challenge for Ward
沃德面臨的最大的挑戰
is to get off to a faster start than is customary for him.
是他要比平時更快進入攻擊狀態
Micky Ward, a notoriously slow starter in big fights,
米奇﹒沃德是在大賽中出了名的慢熱型選手
Shea Neary, an ultra-fast starter.
而西爾則是個超快速攻擊型選手
And that's the question that hovers over round one.
第一回合的懸念正在于此
Will Ward be ready for the fight?
沃德做好大戰的准備了嗎？
Already, Shea Neary starts taking it to him on the ropes!
才一開場，西爾已經讓沃德陷入險境
And Neary going to the body, which is Ward's specialty.
轉而攻擊身體，而這恰恰是沃德的專長
Neary bangs Ward to the body.
西爾猛擊沃德的身體
And a big uppercut by Neary.
緊接猛一記上鉤拳
Neary leads off with a good left jab.
內瑞以一記漂亮的左刺拳展開攻擊
- Come on, Micky! - Keeps Ward off balance,
- 加油，米奇！ - 使沃德失去平衡
jabbing here and there.
用刺拳不停猛擊
There's a good left hook by Neary as he stepped in on Ward.
內瑞靠近沃德，以一記漂亮的左勾拳攻擊
Ward not able to deal with him very well when Neary stands at range like this.
如果內瑞一直靠近打，沃德就不能很好還手
- Come on! - That's it! Get him!
- 加油！ - 就是這樣！打倒他！
And a left hook lands up top from Micky Ward.
米奇﹒沃德用左勾拳攻擊西爾頭部
Neary digging his own right hand to the body.
內瑞不停用右拳攻擊對方身體
They trade shots at close range.
他們在近距離內互相攻擊
Ward, he's trying to match Neary blow for blow
沃德試圖以牙還牙
and now Neary starts to come on and take the last 30 seconds of the round...
但內瑞開始加大攻擊力度 充分利用第一回合剩下的三十秒
How about that?
感覺怎么樣？
Break!
分開！
Tremendous barrage in the first minute. Just look at this.
第一分鐘就有如此漂亮密集進攻，看看吧
- Unbelievable. - What a great round one!
- 難以置信 - 第一回合太精彩了！
Ward is gonna have to pick up the tempo
沃德必須要加快速度
and beat him with volumes of punching.
以大量的出拳攻擊對手
No doubt, Neary is a better boxer.
毫無疑問內瑞是個更為出色的拳擊手
Four hard right hands... Neary has belted in the last minute.
在最后一分鐘內瑞四記重拳
Quicker than Ward, more assertive than Ward,
比沃德更快，更果斷
surer of what he wants to do.
也更確信自己該怎么做
They're standing and trading shots at the center of the ring.
他們站在拳擊場中央互相攻擊
Ward's gonna have to step it up a little bit more
沃德必須要比現在的進攻
than he is right now.
更快一些才行
Micky Ward's corner taking a real deep look
米奇的助手正在審視
at what's going on now.
場上局勢
And his family at ringside well aware he's stepping up in class.
他在場外的家人清楚的知道他正逐漸出擊
Ward has fallen to the pedal. He's gotta be more aggressive.
沃德的攻擊很無力，他應該更具攻擊性
He can't just try to wait until everything is perfect.
他不能一直等所謂的完美時機
His dominance over Micky Ward is increasing as the fight goes on
西爾的壓倒性優勢會隨比賽的進行增加
because his technical plan was the right one and he's executing it.
因為他的技朮戰略是正確且在施行的
Punches like these make it seem...
這樣出拳讓整場比賽看起來
...that it's now Neary's fight.
是內瑞一個人的戰爭
Ward hasn't been in this kind of war
沃德從未參加過這種比賽
with this strong of fighter as Neary.
面對像內瑞這樣如此強大的對手
They are trying to hurt each other with every punch.
他們試圖只用猛擊來傷害對方
They've tested each other's will, now they're testing each other's skill.
他們已經考驗過彼此的意志力 現在考驗的是雙方的技朮
And Ward wobbled there by a right cross from Neary!
沃德被內瑞的右交叉拳打得站立不穩
Ward hurting now. His legs are gone.
沃德現在受傷了，他的腿不能動彈
Neary goes to the body as he tries to finish Micky.
內瑞開始攻擊他的身體，試圖結束比賽
Vicious body shots from Neary.
都是很毒辣的身體攻擊
And Ward still doesn't even try to move off the ropes!
沃德都不試著離開圍繩！
I don't know if he can, Jim.
我不知道他還有沒有機會，吉姆
He's waiting for Neary to punch himself out.
他等著內瑞把他打出局
Down goes Micky Ward! He may be out.
米奇倒下了，他有可能會出局
That ain't fuckin' it!
他媽夠了！
- One... two... - Come on! That's it!
- 1，2 - 對！就是那樣！
- That's my boy! - Forward! Forward! Come on!
- 我的好小子！ - 向前！向前！上！
Ward is out on his feet.
沃德的雙腳已不聽使喚
Loser! Go back to America!
輸家！滾回美國去吧！
- This could be it for Micky Ward. - Dicky, give him the fuckin' stool.
- 米奇可能就這樣結束比賽了 - 迪奇，給他一張凳子
Charlene, will you get the fuck outta here.
沙琳，別攪合
He needs to fuckin' sit down!
他需要坐下！
His brother's got Ward jumping to wake up his legs.
他哥哥試圖用跳躍來喚醒沃德的雙腿
I think this could be Ward's last chance to turn this fight around.
我覺得這有可能是 沃德的最后一次反轉戰局的機會了
It's Micky Ward against the aggressiveness
現在是米奇﹒沃德在抵抗 攻擊猛烈，出拳利落的西爾﹒內瑞
If you don't have your defense up, you can really get hurt.
如果不加強防備，真的會受傷的
He's making it very difficult for Micky Ward.
他讓米奇處境非常艱難
I don't think he's gonna get into it at this rate.
照這樣下去，我覺得他勝算不大
This is a survival mode...
這是你死我亡
Are you like me? Was just good enough to fight Sugar Ray?
你像我一樣嗎？ 強大到可以與舒格﹒雷抗衡？
Never had to win, did I?
我不一定要贏，一定嗎？
You gotta do more in there. You gotta win a title.
你還要更加努力，你會獲得冠軍
For you, for me, for Lowell.
為你，為我，為了洛厄爾
This is your time, all right? You take it.
輪到你表現了，好嗎？把握好
I had my time and I blew it. You don't have to.
我原本有機會的，但是搞砸了 你不必重蹈覆轍
All right? You fuckin' get out there,
現在你他媽的趕緊上場
and use all the shit that you've been through,
用你練得純熟的技朮
all the shit we've gone through over the fuckin' years
和這些年你所付出的努力
and you put it in that ring right now. This is yours. This is fuckin' yours.
是時候在拳擊場上發泄了 這是屬于你的機會，屬于你的
OK. Fuckin' head, body, head, body.
好，“頭，身體，頭，身體”
Say it back to me. Fuckin' say it back to me.
跟我重復一遍，該死的，重復!
- Head, body, head, body.
- “頭，身體，頭，身體”
Get in your mind this is fucking yours. Fuckin' do it.
銘刻到腦海，冠軍是你的，放手一搏
Stay off the fuckin' ropes.
別他媽的老靠在繩子上
If I'm in Micky Ward's corner tonight,
如果今晚我是米奇﹒沃德的助手的話
I thinking if he doesn't pick things up this round and get going,
會想如果他這一輪還拿不出什么本事來的話
he'll just get totally wiped out.
他將會徹底被淘汰
Off the ropes! Get off the ropes, Mick!
遠離繩子！遠離繩子！米奇！
Once again, Ward against the ropes as Neary is free to attack.
又一次，沃德倚著繩子任由內瑞攻擊
What are you doing? Come on, Mick!
你在干什么？上，米奇
Sometimes if you wanna win, you gotta be something that you're not.
有時候你必須要成為一個完全不同的人 才有可能獲得成功
Come on!
上！
Off the fuckin' ropes, Mick, that ain't it!
離開繩子，老兄！那不是對手！
Neary continues to pound away.
內瑞的拳頭暴風雨般落在米奇身上
Don't take no abuse! This is your time Micky! It's up to you!
別受辱了！輪到你表現自己了，米奇！
- Two big misses by Neary! - That's it! That's it!
- 內瑞打空兩拳！ - 就是這樣！就是這樣！
Ward seemingly getting his legs back.
看起來沃德的腿找回知覺了
He backs Neary off.
他打得內瑞后退
- Ward trades his way back. - That's it!
- 他開始報復了 - 就是那樣！
Ward nods as if to say, "Come on!"
沃德點頭，仿佛在說“放馬過來！”
"Come on, let's fight!"
“來啊，我們來大干一場”
Just imagine if you bought a ticket.
當然如果你買了票只能自己想象了
Closer and closer to Neary's ribcage.
沃德出拳離內瑞的胸膛越來越近
This is becoming Micky Ward's fight.
局面開始傾向于米奇
And a left hook to the body and an uppercut lands
一記左勾拳，又來一記上勾拳
- and now he backs Neary off. - Head, body, head fuckin' body!
- 現在他把內瑞打的節節敗退 - “頭，身體，頭，身體”
Ward hurt Neary with a body shot.
沃德打中了內瑞的身體
Ward hurts him again with that left to the body.
再用左拳猛擊身體
Oh, and that one plants Neary on his butt.
哦，內瑞第一次倒地了
First time in 23 professional fights
23場職業賽中第一次
- that Shea Neary has been down. - This is it! This is it!
- 西爾﹒內瑞被打倒在地 - 就是這樣！就是這樣！
This is it, Micky!
就是這樣，米奇！
Keep going! Don't look at me for it! Take it to him!
保持狀態！不要看我！全力攻擊他！
- Come on, Micky, get in there! - Ward lands a huge left hook!
- 上，米奇，全力以赴！ - 沃德又猛來一記左勾拳
As Micky Ward pounds away!
他發力了！
Goes to the body with the left hook! Lands the uppercut again!
用左勾拳猛擊對手身體，又一記上勾拳！
Neary down for the second time.
內瑞第二次倒地
Mickey Vann's gonna stop it there.
米奇要結束這場比賽了
"Irish" Micky Ward with a big eighth-round TKO!
“愛爾蘭人”米奇﹒沃德 第八回合技朮性壓倒對手！
He's done it again.
他又一次做到了
The grinding, gutty Micky Ward pulls out another big victory!
備受折磨但大膽出擊的米奇﹒沃德 又獲得了一場大勝！
You're the champion of the world, Mick! You're the fuckin' champ of the world!
你成為了世界冠軍，米奇！ 你他媽的成了世界冠軍了
You fuckin' did it!
你做到了！
Oh, you're the best!
你是最棒的！
- Oh, I love you! - My boy's the champion of the world!
- 愛死你了！ - 我兒子是世界冠軍了！
I love you!
我愛你！
This town always said, you're a fuckin' boxer, right?
這個小鎮的人以前一直說 你是個狗日的拳擊手，對嗎？
He thought he was a piece of shit. He put Lowell back on the map, you know?
他以前總是沒有自信 但他現在重新給洛厄爾帶來了榮耀
- We. - I tell ya...
- 是我們 - 我告訴你
- No, but hold on.
- 不，等會
Who used to be the pride of Lowell?
誰曾經是“洛厄爾之驕傲”？
Right here. Who's the pride of Lowell now?
是我，誰現在是“洛厄爾之驕傲”？
Right there. That's how it's meant to be, you know?
是他，這是注定的，你知道嗎？
Handin' it down to him.
這叫做傳承
Nothin' better than that.
沒有比這更好的了，沒有比這更好的了
He did it. I gotta go. I gotta go.
他做到了，我該走了，我該走了
Oh, look at cabbage head. Boo Boo! Quacka!
哦，看那個癮君子布布！哇哇！
- What's up buddy? - Boo, where's your teeth?
- 怎么了，兄弟？ - 阿布，你牙呢？
Oh, I'm under arrest! Let's go, move it out!
我被逮捕了，快走，離開這！
It's been real, ain't it?
這是真實的，對嗎？
It's been real, it's been unreal. It's been a great experience.
既是真實的，也是虛幻的 總之是一段精彩的經歷
Just glad it's done, finally,
我慶幸終于拍完了
and thanks to everyone so much, from the bottom of my heart.
我從心底非常感謝大家
Thanks so much, all you Hollywood people.
謝謝所有的好萊塢工作人員
Now you know what I mean when I say I can't get a word in.
現在你知道我說插不上嘴是什么意思了
I'm telling ya. He'll never get a word in.
我告訴你們，他從來都插不上嘴
- All right, thank you. - Thank you.
- 好了，謝謝 - 謝謝
Peace, everybody.
各位，愿世界和平